<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Impact on Azhar Khan</title>
    <link>https://azharkhan.in/tags/impact/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Impact on Azhar Khan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>azhar932@icloud.com (Azhar Khan)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>azhar932@icloud.com (Azhar Khan)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2016 21:34:41 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://azharkhan.in/tags/impact/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Eating Animals</title>
        <link>https://azharkhan.in/notes/eating-animals/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2016 21:34:41 +0100</pubDate>
        <author>azhar932@icloud.com (Azhar Khan)</author>
        <guid>https://azharkhan.in/notes/eating-animals/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Thoughts and notes taken from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/6604712-eating-animals?from_search=true&#34;&gt;Eating Animals&lt;/a&gt; by Jonathan Safran Foer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;thoughts&#34;&gt;Thoughts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A real eye opener on the factory faming industry. This book will make you seriously consider your meet consumption. If not for ethical or environmental reasons then perhaps for the benefit of your health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Food serves two parallel purposes: it nourishes and it helps you remember.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is something about eating animals that tends to polarize: never eat them or never sincerely question eating them; become an activist or disdain activists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It raises significant philosophical questions and is a $140 billion–plus a year industry that occupies nearly a third of the land on the planet, shapes ocean ecosystems, and may well determine the future of earth’s climate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have waged war, or rather let a war be waged, against all of the animals we eat. This war is new and has a name: factory farming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than any set of practices, factory farming is a mind-set: reduce production costs to the absolute minimum and systematically ignore or “externalize” such costs as environmental degradation, human disease, and animal suffering. For thousands of years, farmers took their cues from natural processes. Factory farming considers nature an obstacle to be overcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Children confront us with our paradoxes and hypocrisies, and we are exposed. You need to find an answer for every why—Why do we do this? Why don’t we do that?—and often there isn’t a good one. So you say, simply, because.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;blockquote class=&#34;PullQuote PullQuote--right&#34;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
            Animal agriculture makes a 40% greater contribution to global warming than all transportation in the world combined; it is the number one cause of climate change.
            
            
        &lt;/p&gt;
        
            &lt;figcaption&gt;&amp;mdash; Jonathan Safran Foer&lt;/figcaption&gt;
        
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chickens once had a life expectancy of fifteen to twenty years, but the modern broiler is typically killed at around six weeks. Their daily growth rate has increased roughly 400 percent.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The average shrimp-trawling operation throws 80 to 90 percent of the sea animals it captures overboard, dead or dying, as bycatch. (Endangered species amount to much of this bycatch.) Shrimp account for only 2 percent of global seafood by weight, but shrimp trawling accounts for 33 percent of global bycatch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cruelty depends on an understanding of cruelty, and the ability to choose against it. Or to choose to ignore it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How much do I value creating a socially comfortable situation, and how much do I value acting socially responsible?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the livestock sector is responsible for 18 percent of greenhouse gas emissions, around 40 percent more than the entire transport sector—&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;omnivores contribute seven times the volume of greenhouse gases that vegans do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Animal agriculture] should be a major policy focus when dealing with problems of land degradation, climate change and air pollution, water shortage and water pollution and loss of biodiversity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We live in a world in which it’s conventional to treat an animal like a hunk of wood and extreme to treat an animal like an animal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No one fired a pistol to mark the start of the race to the bottom. The earth just tilted and everyone slid into the hole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What the industry figured out—and this was the real revolution—is that you don’t need healthy animals to make a profit. Sick animals are more profitable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The highest rates of osteoporosis are seen in countries where people consume the most dairy foods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The entire goliath of the food industry is ultimately driven and determined by the choices we make as the waiter gets impatient for our order or in the practicalities and whimsies of what we load into our shopping carts or farmers’-market bags.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is the reason the factory farm system is failing and won’t work over the long term: it’s created a food industry whose primary concern isn’t feeding people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At one level, this is the result of the normal process of corporations pursuing profit by making sure they have access to resources their competitors don’t. There is, obviously, a lot of money at stake here: billions of dollars, which could either be spread among a handful of megacorporations or among hundreds of thousands of small farmers. But&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The factory farm has succeeded by divorcing people from their food, eliminating farmers, and ruling agriculture by corporate fiat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just how destructive does a culinary preference have to be before we decide to eat something else? If contributing to the suffering of billions of animals that live miserable lives and (quite often) die in horrific ways isn’t motivating, what would be? If being the number one contributor to the most serious threat facing the planet (global warming) isn’t enough, what is? And if you are tempted to put off these questions of conscience, to say not now, then when?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day, factory farming isn’t about feeding people; it’s about money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If animal agriculture has become a joke, perhaps this is the punch line: even Bill Niman has said he would no longer eat Niman Ranch beef.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not in the end a complicated position. Nor is it a veiled argument for vegetarianism. It is an argument for vegetarianism, but it’s also an argument for another, wiser animal agriculture and more honorable omnivory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not in the end a complicated position. Nor is it a veiled argument for vegetarianism. It is an argument for vegetarianism, but it’s also an argument for another, wiser animal agriculture and more honorable omnivory. If we are not given the option to live without violence, we are given the choice to center our meals around harvest or slaughter, husbandry or war. We have chosen slaughter. We have chosen war. That’s the truest version of our story of eating animals. Can we tell a new story?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The three years I spent writing this book, for example, saw the first documentation that livestock contribute more to global warming than anything else; saw the first major research institution (the Pew Commission) recommend the total phaseout of multiple dominant intensive-confinement practices; saw the first state (Colorado) illegalize common factory farm practices (gestation and veal crates) as a result of negotiations with industry (rather than campaigns against industry); saw the first supermarket chain of any kind (Whole Foods) commit to a systematic and extensive program of animal welfare labeling; and saw the first major national newspaper (the New York Times) editorialize against factory farming as a whole, arguing that “animal husbandry has been turned into animal abuse,” and “manure… has been turned into toxic waste.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve restricted myself to mostly discussing how our food choices affect the ecology of our planet and the lives of its animals, but I could have just as easily made the entire book about public health, workers’ rights, decaying rural communities, or global poverty—all of which are profoundly affected by factory farming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To accept the factory farm feels inhuman. To accept the factory farm—to feed the food it produces to my family, to support it with my money—would make me less myself, less my grandmother’s grandson, less my son’s father. This is what my grandmother meant when she said, “If nothing matters, there’s nothing to save.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>The Challenger’s Almanac</title>
        <link>https://azharkhan.in/notes/challengers/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2016 21:34:41 +0100</pubDate>
        <author>azhar932@icloud.com (Azhar Khan)</author>
        <guid>https://azharkhan.in/notes/challengers/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Thought’s and notes from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/28605442-the-challenger-s-almanac?ac=1&amp;amp;from_search=true&#34;&gt;The Challenger’s Almanac&lt;/a&gt; by Mark Anderson.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;thoughts&#34;&gt;Thoughts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hate to admit it — I had this book on my shelf for a few years before I finally came to read it. Wish i&amp;rsquo;d picked it up sooner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re anything like me then the stories in this book will make a lot of sense to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you believe in quality over quantity. If you consider yourself a creative thinker — an artist, a maker or an entrepreneur of sorts — with a tendency to challenge the way things are done, then you&amp;rsquo;ll have a lot of time for this book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the companies featured were started by people questioning the way things are done. Using lateral thinking as their weapon, they&amp;rsquo;ve made it their mission in life to solve problems personally faced. Problems they are passionate about trying to fix — and not just for the money — but because they genuinely want to do good in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book is also packed full of related reading and recommended talks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Challenger brands are &lt;strong&gt;businesses with purpose&lt;/strong&gt;. Businesses who are  prepared to break the rules. Businesses that manage to blend having a positive impact on the world with being financially successful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Often naivety leads companies to new and creative ways of working.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most challenger companies begin life as &lt;strong&gt;side projects&lt;/strong&gt;, created through passion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They lack experience and a natural right to create. &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;re not experts but why should that matter&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All successful people fail.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Transparent sense of purpose and a force of good challenging ethics and ideology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Solving problems. Seeing something that needs to be done better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Proof of concept&lt;/strong&gt; — &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;I started telling people my idea as if it already existed. I had customers. I had a business&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;. Reminds me of &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Buffer&amp;rsquo;s landing page POC&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ask for help&lt;/strong&gt; — you can&amp;rsquo;t do it alone. Passion and excitement is a great bargaining tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You need a purpose — that you love and others can believe in — and an idea to make something better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Procrastiwork&lt;/strong&gt; — work you do when you are putting off other work. &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;The work you do when you&amp;rsquo;re procrastinating is probably the work you should be doing for the rest of your life&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let tiny victories pave your path. By doing so your path will present itself. Don&amp;rsquo;t set overly ambitious goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Procrastiwork&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; can help you maintain momentum with client work as you switch from project to project to keep excitement high.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take time to understand what you love about the work your doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;The Holstee Mainifesto&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; – a company should be built around a lifestyle rather than the other way around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seeing business as a way to make an impact on the world and contribute to a cause you feel strongly about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only person you should listen to is the customer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ask for advise from other companies and people that inspire you. You&amp;rsquo;ll be surprised at how much people are willing to share about what they have learnt and the mistakes they&amp;rsquo;ve made.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Figure out your message and put your energy into getting it across.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;The most satisfying thing is knowing your business is a force of good and can make a difference to a cause you feel strongly about.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Find a mentor&lt;/strong&gt; — someone who has been there before and can stear you in the right direction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On public speaking&lt;/strong&gt; — understand your audience so you can get an idea of what they want to know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10,000 hours&lt;/strong&gt; — in order to be an expert you have to spend 10,000 hours (approx. 10 years) practicing it. An idea taken from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/3228917-outliers&#34;&gt;Outliers by Malcom Gladwell&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Trust your own judgement. Have faith in your decisions. Take advise from people you respect an be prepared to act on it.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Behind most Challenger brands there is usually someone on a mission to solve a problem they have encountered in their lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Challengers change the way we think, act, feel, see and behave using design to express their vision.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not about building it fast, but building it right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s not the government who is going to solve our environmental issues, it&amp;rsquo;s business.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Everytime I&amp;rsquo;ve done the right thing for the environment, i&amp;rsquo;ve made a profit&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; — Yvon Chouinard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Business is the most powerful man-made force on the planet, so it is important for businesses to use that power to do the most good. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if a business is the biggest. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if it&amp;rsquo;s the fastest growing. It matters if a business is the best in the world at being the best for the world.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;What matters most is not simply the ability to make money, but the ability of a business to create value for its customers, employees, community, the environment and other stakeholders.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Share your mission with your employees. This creates more engaged employees and spurs innovative thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Expand your network. Share your results. Put your practices and policies into writing, this helps everyone adhere to goals as the company grows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Anyone Paradigm&lt;/strong&gt; — &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;We are full service, and or company will serve anyone&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;.  Don&amp;rsquo;t try and serve everyone, this approach isn&amp;rsquo;t strategic enough. Focus on serving quality customers, not a quantity of customers. It&amp;rsquo;s better to know who you will not serve, and what services you will not perform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A company can become strategic by narrowly defining who it is they serve best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recognising you have limitations is strategic, not weak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Business strategy is to know your greatest skill, and offer the world only that.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The &amp;ldquo;what we believe&amp;rdquo; in document&lt;/strong&gt; — helps to keep the wrong customers out. If they do not align with your beliefs, they might not be the best fit for your company. A good way to find the right clients. Alignment is key.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of enterprise is to produce value for customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you care more about customers than profit, then you can take a limited number of clients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be honest.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Make products that last&lt;/strong&gt; — simple sustainable design. Design that matters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People remember good stories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn the rules in order to break them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pursue passion projects.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most valuable currency is &lt;strong&gt;time not money&lt;/strong&gt;. Don&amp;rsquo;t strive for the biggest profits but instead find the time for things that matter to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pursue and develop creative ideas.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Creativity is our currency; something we promise and our clients expect&amp;rdquo;. Get away from you desk if you want this to work.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;We all need time and space to experiment and cultivate creativity if our ideas are really going to be fresh&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Allowing time and space for incidental thoughts, ideas, conversations that you only get from actually meeting someone really does reap rewards and nurture lasting, valuable relationships.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Profit with principles. It&amp;rsquo;s not just economic profit, but a positive social and environmental impact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have a vision. Consider the type of Culture you want to create.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t command but collaborate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nurture and develop individuals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make money not your only priority.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be honest and transparent with your communication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without purpose you have no meaning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great achievement is talent plus preparation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Practice isn&amp;rsquo;t the thing you do once you&amp;rsquo;re good. It&amp;rsquo;s the thing you do that makes you good&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; - Malcolm Gladwell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t be afraid to prototype in public&lt;/strong&gt;- &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;put yourself out there and see where the velcro sticks&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;A brand is not a logo, or a pantone colour. A brand ius a promise.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;How much can I give, rather than How much can I take.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Know what it is you&amp;rsquo;re trying to say, say clearly, and then do what you said you were going to do, when you said you were going to do it. That is the rule for business.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;They [Entrepreneurs] are not just risk takers, they are believers in the unproven, untested, and the unlikely&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;A misconception of business is that you need bags of experience to start.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Naïve Optimism&lt;/strong&gt;: To not get sidetracked by what can&amp;rsquo;t be done. There are no rules. Only opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;All too often, leaders of companies are willing to Sacrifice people to save the numbers, rather than sacrificing the numbers to save the people.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Leadership is the choice to offer protection to those in our care. It&amp;rsquo;s simply, &amp;lsquo;I will risk my life for the good of my people&amp;rsquo;. That&amp;rsquo;s why you own the title of leader.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;The genius of one never sold anything. As human beings, we&amp;rsquo;re better together.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Why you do what you do, not what you do. That&amp;rsquo;s a good place to start.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*&amp;ldquo;We all have to question, and be willing to break the rules.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;If you want to remain number 1 you have to think like number 2.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Fear regret, not failure.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;rdquo;..find your &amp;lsquo;why&amp;rsquo;, identify your mission, define your belief, write your manifesto. Do all these things, and then build upon them.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>