<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Page on Azhar Khan</title>
    <link>https://azharkhan.in/page/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Page on Azhar Khan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>azhar932@icloud.com (Azhar Khan)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>azhar932@icloud.com (Azhar Khan)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 14:23:25 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://azharkhan.in/page/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Designing and building an eCommerce website</title>
        <link>https://azharkhan.in/ecommerce/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 14:23:25 +0100</pubDate>
        <author>azhar932@icloud.com (Azhar Khan)</author>
        <guid>https://azharkhan.in/ecommerce/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This page briefly explains how I approach designing and building an eCommerce website, how much it costs and how long it takes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This should give you an idea of whether I&amp;rsquo;m the right person to design and build your new website and help you start selling products online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-the-process&#34;&gt;About the process&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Essentially, what we’ll be doing is designing and building a bespoke website which represents your brand and meets your expectations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First we’ll discuss the requirements for the website, then set the goals for the project. From here we’ll explore design ideas and decide the appropriate direction to take. Then I’ll work on some designs based on our discussion and decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you’re happy with the design and any required revisions have been made, I’ll build the design in code, and add initial content so we’re ready to test before launch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll keep the project as dynamic and fluid as possible, and stay in regular contact throughout the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to building your website, behind the design and code your shop will be powered by a popular eCommerce solution called Shopify.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-shopify&#34;&gt;About Shopify&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.shopify.com/&#34;&gt;Shopify&lt;/a&gt; takes care of the difficult parts of eCommerce – such as taking payments, managing orders and tracking product inventory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using Shopify makes it much faster and more affordable to get up and running selling products online via your own website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The platform has excellent support and a whole host of integrations to extend the functionality of your website, should you want to add custom features or wish to scale in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, Shopify is a great product that’s trusted by lots of businesses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;shopify-fees&#34;&gt;Shopify fees&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s important to make you aware that Shopify charge a monthly subscription fee. Shopify’s Basic package is &lt;code&gt;$29/month&lt;/code&gt; and this is usually more than sufficient for most small businesses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Basic package price includes hosting your website, unlimited products, 24/7 support, and allows you to assign inventory to up to 4 physical shop locations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shopify also charges a small fee of around 2.0% for online credit card payments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find more information about Shopify’s fees &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.shopify.co.uk/pricing&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;previous-project&#34;&gt;Previous project&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To give you an idea of how your eCommerce website might function, I previously designed a Shopify powered website for &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.albioncycling.com/&#34;&gt;albioncycling.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a detailed look at my process for this project, you can find a case study here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://harrycresswell.com/projects/albion/&#34;&gt;Albioncycling.com case study&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;client-testimonials&#34;&gt;Client testimonials&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are a couple of testimonials in case you’re interested to read what a few of my previous clients have to say:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Harry manages to at once meet seriously impressive digital skills with a great eye for design and an attention to detail that can satisfy even a client with OCD&amp;hellip;Nothing is ever too much trouble.”
– Rose Beer @ Rose Beer Beauty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Harry and Luke were a pleasure to work with from start to finish. Creative in their ideas and highly efficient in their execution, they are a formidable partnership. Our website and online store brief presented Harry and Luke with a number of creative and technical challenges, which they solved with aplomb and with minimum fuss.” – Charlie Stewart @ Albion Cycling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-i-charge&#34;&gt;What I charge&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To keep things simple, I charge a flat fee of &lt;strong&gt;£1500&lt;/strong&gt; to design and build an eCommerce website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I request a &lt;strong&gt;50% payment upfront&lt;/strong&gt; to make sure we’re both committed to the project, and &lt;strong&gt;50% on completion&lt;/strong&gt;. I only request the final payment once you’ve confirmed you’re happy with the final outcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This fee covers any technical help you may need to get up and running, including guidance using Shopify’s content management system to manage your products and process orders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This price won’t change and there won’t be any other hidden costs involved. However, if you require content creation such as copywriting or photography, this can be discussed at an additional cost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-long-it-takes&#34;&gt;How long it takes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2-3 weeks&lt;/strong&gt; should be more than enough time to design and build the website, however I usually allow &lt;strong&gt;4 weeks&lt;/strong&gt; as a buffer, just in case there are any issues or setbacks during the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This timeframe is largely dependent on how far along you are with the content for the website, and how clear you are about what you want to achieve from the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creating content for a website is often the most time-consuming part. This includes writing copy for pages (about page, delivery and returns, privacy policy, etc), photographing products and organising initial imagery for launch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you already have content for you website that’s great, we should be able to complete the project within this timeframe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you haven’t even thought about content yet, or only have some, then not to worry.
We can discuss the best direction to take before getting the project underway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;next-steps&#34;&gt;Next steps&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If this sounds good and you’re happy with my approach, then please fill out the project planner via the link below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://harrycresswell.typeform.com/to/JlvvVS&#34;&gt;eCommerce Website Project Planner&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The aim of the project planner is to get a better understanding of what stage you’re currently at with the planning of your website, and what’s required from the project. This will help make sure we’re both on the same page before we begin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following this we can jump on a call to discuss the project in more detail and identify any specific requirements. Then, if all is well we can get the project underway.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Likes</title>
        <link>https://azharkhan.in/likes/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2020 13:04:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>azhar932@icloud.com (Azhar Khan)</author>
        <guid>https://azharkhan.in/likes/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This page collects my starred articles in &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Feedbin&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;. I stole the idea from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.robinrendle.com/notes/rss-favorites&#34;&gt;Robin&lt;/a&gt;, who learn’t about it from &lt;a href=&#34;https://daverupert.com/likes/&#34;&gt;Dave&lt;/a&gt;, who was inspired by &lt;a href=&#34;https://css-tricks.com/how-to-fetch-and-parse-rss-feeds-in-javascript/&#34;&gt;this post from Chris&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final bit of magic &lt;a href=&#34;https://hankchizljaw.com/wrote/jamstack-ifttt-and-netlify:-a-power-trio/#heading-back-to-power-trios&#34;&gt;I learn’t from Andy&lt;/a&gt;. It involves using &lt;a href=&#34;https://ifttt.com/&#34;&gt;IFTTT&lt;/a&gt; to watch for changes to &lt;a href=&#34;https://feedbin.com/starred/e8b05a0c7620135a0be3cffa18aa898b.xml&#34;&gt;my Feedbin RSS feed&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So whenever I favourite a new article in Feedbin, IFTTT sends a POST request to Netlify, which then triggers a build hook and pulls in the new articles.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Uses</title>
        <link>https://azharkhan.in/uses/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2019 11:27:43 +0100</pubDate>
        <author>azhar932@icloud.com (Azhar Khan)</author>
        <guid>https://azharkhan.in/uses/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My office setup, and the tools I use from day to day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hardware&#34;&gt;Hardware&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apple 15-inch MacBook Pro 2015&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.apple.com/uk/shop/product/MLA22B/A/magic-keyboard-british-english&#34;&gt;Apple Magic Keyboard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.apple.com/uk/shop/product/MJ2R2Z/A/magic-trackpad-2-silver&#34;&gt;Apple Magic Trackpad 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.apple.com/airpods-pro/&#34;&gt;Apple AirPods Pro&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apple iPhone X&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.co.uk/inch-Dell-P2415Q-IPS-Monitor/dp/B00QAJ2MOM/ref=sr_1_1?dchild=1&amp;amp;keywords=Dell+P2415Q&amp;amp;qid=1584572080&amp;amp;sr=8-1&#34;&gt;Dell P2415Q Monitor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.therooststand.com/&#34;&gt;Roost Laptop Stand&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vitsoe.com/gb/606/components#desk-shelf&#34;&gt;606 Universal Shelving System Desk shelf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hermanmiller.com/en_gb/products/seating/office-chairs/aeron-chairs/&#34;&gt;Herman Miller Aeron Chair&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ebay.co.uk/i/333518493626?chn=ps&#34;&gt;Logitech x-230 speakers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;software&#34;&gt;Software&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://1password.com/downloads/mac/&#34;&gt;1Password&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ia.net/writer&#34;&gt;iAWriter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.notion.so/&#34;&gt;Notion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dropbox.com/&#34;&gt;Dropbox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://nordvpn.com/&#34;&gt;NordVPN&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.alfredapp.com/&#34;&gt;Alfred&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.figma.com/&#34;&gt;Figma&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mozilla.org/&#34;&gt;Firefox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://feedbin.com/&#34;&gt;Feedbin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ifttt.com/&#34;&gt;IFTTT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://zapier.com/&#34;&gt;Zapier&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://airtable.com/&#34;&gt;Airtable&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mailchimp.com/&#34;&gt;Mailchimp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://numi.app/&#34;&gt;Numi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/calendar/about/&#34;&gt;Google Calendar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.co.uk/&#34;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://cleanmymac.com/&#34;&gt;CleanMyMacX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;development&#34;&gt;Development&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTML&#34;&gt;HTML&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.w3.org/Style/CSS/&#34;&gt;CSS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.xfive.co/blog/itcss-scalable-maintainable-css-architecture/&#34;&gt;ITCSS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://suitcss.github.io/&#34;&gt;SuitCSS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sass-lang.com/&#34;&gt;Sass&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/JavaScript&#34;&gt;JavaScript&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://nodejs.org/en/&#34;&gt;Node&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://reactjs.org/&#34;&gt;React&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://graphql.org/&#34;&gt;GraphQL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.npmjs.com/&#34;&gt;NPM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://git-scm.com/&#34;&gt;Git&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://hyper.is/&#34;&gt;Hyper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://code.visualstudio.com/&#34;&gt;VSCode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.11ty.dev/&#34;&gt;Eleventy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gatsbyjs.org/&#34;&gt;Gatsby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sanity.io/&#34;&gt;Sanity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://forestry.io/&#34;&gt;Forestry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.netlify.com/&#34;&gt;Netlify&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://cloudinary.com/&#34;&gt;Cloudinary&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This page was inspired by &lt;a href=&#34;https://wesbos.com/uses/&#34;&gt;Wes Bos&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Privacy Policy</title>
        <link>https://azharkhan.in/privacy/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 13:16:53 +0100</pubDate>
        <author>azhar932@icloud.com (Azhar Khan)</author>
        <guid>https://azharkhan.in/privacy/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In compliance with the data and privacy laws (“GDPR”), effective of May 25th 2018 and in an effort to be more transparent with those who who choose to share data with me, I have assembled the following information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-data-i-collect&#34;&gt;What data I collect&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only data I collect is the name and email address of those who sign up for &lt;a href=&#34;https://azharkhan.in/newsletter/&#34;&gt;my weekly newsletter&lt;/a&gt; via the sign up form on the bottom of each page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-i-do-with-data&#34;&gt;What I do with data&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I only email people who have genuinely signed up to receive my newsletter each week. I do not add contacts, clients or people I meet randomly on the climbing wall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use &lt;a href=&#34;https://kb.mailchimp.com/lists/signup-forms/single-opt-in-vs.-double-opt-in&#34;&gt;double opt-in&lt;/a&gt; during the sign up process to prevent spam accounts and include an unsubscribe link on each and every email I send out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By signing up for my mailing list you are agreeing to receive an email from me containing useful content, once a week on a Friday and that’s it. I have no intention of selling you anything, advertising or passing your data on to any 3rd party services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do not use Google Analytics or any other tracking software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-i-keep-your-data-safe&#34;&gt;How I keep your data safe&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I store your data securely inside my &lt;a href=&#34;https://mailchimp.com/features/landing-pages/&#34;&gt;Mailchimp&lt;/a&gt; account and use a generated password from &lt;a href=&#34;https://1password.com/&#34;&gt;1Password&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Multi-factor_authentication&#34;&gt;two-factor authentication&lt;/a&gt; (2FA) in order to keep it safe. Rest assured, your details aren’t lying around in an old spreadsheet or .csv file somewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Working with me</title>
        <link>https://azharkhan.in/work-with-me/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2018 20:36:08 +0100</pubDate>
        <author>azhar932@icloud.com (Azhar Khan)</author>
        <guid>https://azharkhan.in/work-with-me/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p class=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;
    This page will give you a clear idea of ways we can work together and if I’m the right fit for your next project.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;who-i-am&#34;&gt;Who I am&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My name is Harry Cresswell, I’m an independent designer and front-end web developer from London, England.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve spent the last 7 years helping startup businesses and independent individuals get set up online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-i-do&#34;&gt;What I do&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To put it simply I design and code content based websites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From concept through to launch, I wireframe, prototype and code designs into fully functioning websites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My tools of choice are HTML, CSS and JavaScript. I specialise in creating “Jamstack” websites with Hugo and Eleventy, and eCommerce stores using Shopify.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also implement content management systems using Forestry, Netlify CMS and Sanity, so you can manage the content on your website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are looking for an app developer, or someone to help create a website driven by user data, then I’m not your guy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The websites I build are robust and cost effective to run. They load fast and are optimised for search engines. They aim to meet accessibility standards and be as inclusive as possible, so you can call those who use assistive technologies your customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-i-work&#34;&gt;How I work&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe that communication and collaboration are vital to the success of a project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like to keep the process as dynamic and fluid as possible. We’ll move thoughtfully and efficiently in the most appropriate direction until we find the right solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not afraid to ask questions, sometimes they might sound stupid, but the better I understand your vision, the sooner I can help you create the right product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I won’t disappear for weeks on end then deliver a product which doesn’t meet your expectations. Instead you’ll be involved through every step of product development, so we’re on the same page from start to finish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;who-hires-me&#34;&gt;Who hires me&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I work with startups, small businesses, agencies and individuals who need a web developer with a good understanding of design, who is experienced in launching products online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My clients tend to be those keen to execute ideas, but don’t necessarily have the technical skills to do so. Or those who’d rather save on big agency fees by investing their budget in good design, at an affordable rate, from an independent designer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-i-charge&#34;&gt;What I charge&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My rate varies depending on your situation and needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I charge a flat fee for all projects, so no hourly rate, just a single project price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are an independent individual just starting out, then I will charge a considerable amount less than if you are an established business who has just raised investment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are a non-profit organisation or charity then I will often waiver my fee entirely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;get-in-touch&#34;&gt;Get in touch&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have a project in mind, and you think I might be a good fit, then &lt;a href=&#34;https://azharkhan.in/contact/&#34;&gt;let’s talk about it&lt;/a&gt; and we can take it from there.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Awesome</title>
        <link>https://azharkhan.in/success/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 21:14:42 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>azhar932@icloud.com (Azhar Khan)</author>
        <guid>https://azharkhan.in/success/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Thanks for your message. It’s flying through the internet right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Forgive me if I don’t reply right away, I receive a lot of messages so I tend to pause my inbox to limit distraction from email to once per day. I aim to get back to everyone within 24hrs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;P.S. — If you’re here to check out how this form works and you want to know more about building forms on static sites read my article &lt;a href=&#34;https://azharkhan.in/articles/forms-with-netlify/&#34;&gt;Handling forms on static sites with Netlify&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Ask me anything</title>
        <link>https://azharkhan.in/contact/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2018 14:25:28 +0100</pubDate>
        <author>azhar932@icloud.com (Azhar Khan)</author>
        <guid>https://azharkhan.in/contact/</guid>
        <description>
&lt;p&gt;If you have a question please leave a message, I’m always happy to hear from interesting people doing interesting things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;form class=&#34;Form&#34; name=&#34;contact&#34; id=&#34;ContactForm&#34; method=&#34;POST&#34; netlify-honeypot=&#34;bot-field&#34; action=&#34;https://azharkhan.in/success/&#34; netlify&gt;
    &lt;p class=&#34;u-visually-hidden&#34;&gt;
        &lt;label&gt;Don’t fill this out if you&#39;re human: &lt;input name=&#34;bot-field&#34;&gt;&lt;/label&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;label class=&#34;Form-label&#34; for=&#34;full-name&#34;&gt;Full Name&lt;/label&gt;
    &lt;input class=&#34;Form-input&#34; name=&#34;full-name&#34; type=&#34;text&#34; placeholder=&#34;Your full name&#34; required&gt;
    &lt;label class=&#34;Form-label&#34; for=&#34;email-address&#34;&gt;Email Address&lt;/label&gt;
    &lt;input class=&#34;Form-input&#34; name=&#34;email-address&#34; type=&#34;email&#34; placeholder=&#34;Your email&#34; required&gt;
    &lt;label class=&#34;Form-label&#34; for=&#34;message&#34;&gt;Message&lt;/label&gt;
		&lt;textarea class=&#34;Form-textarea&#34; name=&#34;message&#34; type=&#34;text&#34; placeholder=&#34;Your message...&#34; required&gt;&lt;/textarea&gt;
	&lt;button class=&#34;Form-button Button Button--primary&#34; type=&#34;submit&#34; value=&#34;Submit&#34; id=&#34;Form-submit&#34;&gt;Submit&lt;/button&gt;
&lt;/form&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/harrycresswell&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;find me on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; if that’s more your thing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>How I built this site</title>
        <link>https://azharkhan.in/build/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2018 22:11:02 +0100</pubDate>
        <author>azhar932@icloud.com (Azhar Khan)</author>
        <guid>https://azharkhan.in/build/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p class=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;
    This page shares the technology and techniques I used to build and host this website. 
&lt;/p&gt;
 If you have a specific question &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;drop me a message&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;, I’d be happy to help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;templating&#34;&gt;Templating&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The website is built using a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.staticgen.com/&#34;&gt;static site generator&lt;/a&gt; called &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;. I’m using &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/harrycresswell/harry/tree/master/themes/hc-starter&#34;&gt;a custom theme&lt;/a&gt; I built on top of Hugo for the front-end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;asset-pipeline&#34;&gt;Asset pipeline&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All assets are processed by Hugo using &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/hugo-pipes/&#34;&gt;Hugo Pipes&lt;/a&gt;. This means I no longer need a build tool like Gulp to do stuff like compile SCSS to CSS or concatenate and minify JavaScript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;typography&#34;&gt;Typography&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Typography on the site is set using &lt;a href=&#34;https://css-tricks.com/snippets/css/system-font-stack/&#34;&gt;system defaults&lt;/a&gt;, meaning text will render differently depending on your operating system. Personally I like the way this happens. It’s less of a headache to work with browser inconsistences instead of against them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.madebymike.com.au/writing/fluid-type-calc-examples/&#34;&gt;fluid type mixin developed by Mike Riethmuller&lt;/a&gt; to make it responsive for different screen resolutions. Type sizes are set using 2 modular scales, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.modularscale.com/?1&amp;amp;em&amp;amp;1.2&#34;&gt;5:6 — minor third&lt;/a&gt; for smaller devices and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.modularscale.com/?1&amp;amp;em&amp;amp;1.875&#34;&gt;8:15 — major seventh&lt;/a&gt; for desktop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;css-naming&#34;&gt;CSS naming&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CSS is written in SCSS, and follows &lt;a href=&#34;https://suitcss.github.io/&#34;&gt;SuitCSS&lt;/a&gt;, a component based CSS methodology developed by &lt;a href=&#34;http://nicolasgallagher.com/&#34;&gt;Nicholas Gallagher&lt;/a&gt;. It’s pretty similar to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://getbem.com/&#34;&gt;BEM&lt;/a&gt; method, I just prefer the way it looks. Otherwise theres not much in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I organise my SCSS partials loosely based on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.xfive.co/blog/itcss-scalable-maintainable-css-architecture/&#34;&gt;ITCSS&lt;/a&gt; in terms of order of specificity, however I opted to use a more conventional system for file naming and folder structure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;deployment-and-hosting&#34;&gt;Deployment and hosting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The site is hosted directly from &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/harrycresswell/harry&#34;&gt;a GitHub repository&lt;/a&gt; and served on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://jamstack.org/&#34;&gt;JAMstack&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.netlify.com/&#34;&gt;Netlify&lt;/a&gt;. Netlify is a great CDN which also takes care of TLS certificates for HTTPS, and continuous deployments. That means when I push changes to Github it automatically deploys updates to the live site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the code can be found on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/harrycresswell/harry&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;. Feel free to use it for your own learning and development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;form-handling&#34;&gt;Form handling&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All form handling is taken care of by Netlify, so when a visitor submits the form, Netlify collects the submission and notifies me via email. If you’re interested in how all this works, I wrote about it in &lt;a href=&#34;https://azharkhan.in/articles/forms-with-netlify/&#34;&gt;Static Site Form Handling with Netlify&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;media-storage&#34;&gt;Media storage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All media on the site (images, GIFs etc) is hosted by &lt;a href=&#34;https://cloudinary.com/&#34;&gt;Cloudinary&lt;/a&gt;, a cloud based storage service. This way I’m not committing large media files to GitHub and can avoid slow build times. Cloudinary provides automatic responsive images and compression with &amp;lsquo;transformations&amp;rsquo; set in the URL. You can read &lt;a href=&#34;https://azharkhan.in/articles/cloudinary/&#34;&gt;more about how that works here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any further questions &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:studio@harrycresswell.com&#34;&gt;drop me an email&lt;/a&gt; or a &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/harrycresswell/&#34;&gt;tweet&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;d be more than happy to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Imprint</title>
        <link>https://azharkhan.in/imprint/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2018 22:11:02 +0100</pubDate>
        <author>azhar932@icloud.com (Azhar Khan)</author>
        <guid>https://azharkhan.in/imprint/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p class=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;
    On this page you’ll find legal information about my company and my privacy policy.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;company-info&#34;&gt;Company Info&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://harrycresswell.com/&#34;&gt;Harry Cresswell&lt;/a&gt; is the trading name of:
Studio HC Ltd, Company No. 9442649,
122a Spa Road, London, SE16 3FF.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;privacy-policy&#34;&gt;Privacy Policy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here‘s my &lt;a href=&#34;https://azharkhan.in/privacy&#34;&gt;privacy policy&lt;/a&gt; for those interested in what data I collect, what I do with it and how I keep it safe.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Right now</title>
        <link>https://azharkhan.in/now/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 22:05:42 +0100</pubDate>
        <author>azhar932@icloud.com (Azhar Khan)</author>
        <guid>https://azharkhan.in/now/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m in London, on lockdown due to the Covid-19 Coronavirus outbreak. I’m well, but I’m at home to help prevent the spread. This is how I’m spending my time right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;currently-reading&#34;&gt;Currently Reading&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://every-layout.dev/&#34;&gt;Every Layout&lt;/a&gt; by Haydon Pickering and Andy Bell&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/109800.Wild_Fermentation?ac=1&amp;amp;from_search=true&amp;amp;qid=lMMKTFuhua&amp;amp;rank=1&#34;&gt;Wild Fermentation&lt;/a&gt; by Sandor Ellix Katz&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/6518085-pro-git&#34;&gt;Pro Git&lt;/a&gt; by Scott Chacon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/41009404-dont-make-me-think&#34;&gt;Don’t make me think&lt;/a&gt; by Steve Krug&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;current-projects&#34;&gt;Current Projects&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I’m building a UI style guide generator with Eleventy, which takes a set of &lt;a href=&#34;https://css-tricks.com/what-are-design-tokens/&#34;&gt;design tokens&lt;/a&gt; stored as yaml data and turns them into Sass variables to use in your styles, and JSON to use in your templates. The idea is inspired by &lt;a href=&#34;https://hylia.website/styleguide/&#34;&gt;Andy Bell’s Hylia Starter Kit&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I just launched &lt;a href=&#34;https://locallondon.life&#34;&gt;Local London&lt;/a&gt;, a directory of London food &amp;amp; drink suppliers who deliver to your door. I’m working on the project with my friend Rozzy in response to the Covid-19 outbreak.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Ed_Stephens_1&#34;&gt;Ed&lt;/a&gt; and I have been working on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jobs.angelinvestmentnetwork.co.uk/&#34;&gt;AIN Jobs&lt;/a&gt;, a simple Gatsby powered jobsboard which uses Netlify Forms, Zapier, Airtable and Mailchimp to process data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;currently-studying&#34;&gt;Currently Studying&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://beginnerjavascript.com/&#34;&gt;Beginner JavaScript&lt;/a&gt; by Wes Bos&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ReactJS, GatsbyJS and GraphQL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://timrodenbroeker.de/courses/creative-coding-essentials/&#34;&gt;Creative Coding Essentials&lt;/a&gt; with Tim Rodenbroeker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data driven sites with &lt;a href=&#34;https://11ty.dev/&#34;&gt;Eleventy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sanity.io/&#34;&gt;Sanity.io&lt;/a&gt;, an API based CMS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;German (this one might be here for a while)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Last Updated:&lt;/strong&gt; April 22, 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Page inspired by:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://zenhabits.net/now/&#34;&gt;Zen Habits&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://nownownow.com/about&#34;&gt;Derek Sivers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Newsletter</title>
        <link>https://azharkhan.in/newsletter/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2016 17:23:17 +0100</pubDate>
        <author>azhar932@icloud.com (Azhar Khan)</author>
        <guid>https://azharkhan.in/newsletter/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://us14.campaign-archive.com/home/?u=4e8fba8d0ab4a857159c0104e&amp;amp;id=d6ad2b65ca&#34;&gt;Braintactics&lt;/a&gt; 🤯 is a weekly roundup of articles, tools and tips for product designers and front-end developers. Given a good internet connection I send it once a week, on a Friday morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-topics-does-it-cover&#34;&gt;What topics does it cover?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Expect to find anything related to designing and building things for the web. Topics range from design and web development, to typography, writing, process and productivity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently I’ve included interesting things on:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HTML and CSS fundamentals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Building component libraries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designing accessible color systems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learning CSS grid and flexbox&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Building JAMStack / Serverless websites&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Variable fonts and open source typography&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creating generative artwork with code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;whats-the-format&#34;&gt;What’s the format?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each week I usually begin with one or two thought provoking reads – maybe an article or a quote from a book I’m reading. These may not directly relate to design and development, but dig a little deeper and you should find some helpful lessons to apply to your work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the most part of the email you’ll find links on design and code as you might expect and a section reserved especially for links about typography.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oliver Reichenstein once said; “&lt;a href=&#34;https://ia.net/topics/the-web-is-all-about-typography-period&#34;&gt;Web design is 95% typography&lt;/a&gt;, so it’s only logical to say that a web designer should get good training in the main discipline of shaping written information.“&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I always share something to watch, whether it’s an interesting talk, a short film or a tutorial I’ve lernt something from or found interesting. It tends to be a good way to wrap up the week and start the weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, if I have any of my own work to share I usually put this in at the end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can see &lt;a href=&#34;https://us14.campaign-archive.com/home/?u=4e8fba8d0ab4a857159c0104e&amp;amp;id=d6ad2b65ca&#34;&gt;examples from the archive&lt;/a&gt; anytime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If this sound good to you, leave your email below and join me every Friday morning. Rest assured that &lt;a href=&#34;https://azharkhan.in/privacy/&#34;&gt;your email will be kept safe&lt;/a&gt; at all times.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>