<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Productivity on Azhar Khan</title>
    <link>https://azharkhan.in/tags/productivity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Productivity on Azhar Khan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>azhar932@icloud.com (Azhar Khan)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>azhar932@icloud.com (Azhar Khan)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 11:01:05 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://azharkhan.in/tags/productivity/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Taking notes while you’re out running</title>
        <link>https://azharkhan.in/articles/taking-notes-while-running/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 11:01:05 +0100</pubDate>
        <author>azhar932@icloud.com (Azhar Khan)</author>
        <guid>https://azharkhan.in/articles/taking-notes-while-running/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In a ideal world good ideas arrive just at the right time, when you’re sat at a desk with a pen in hand and paper to write on (or writing software to take notes in). But the reality is that it doesn’t always work this way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a lot of ideas while I’m out running. Running clears my head, it’s a great time think. But it‘s a problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do you write your ideas down without stopping?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe you don’t bother. You could just run faster. Maybe you’ll make it home before you forget your idea. Sometimes this works. And as a nice little bonus you usually record a pretty quick run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But if your brain is in overdrive and the ideas keep coming, it doesn’t work so well. Ideas start stacking up, you replace one with another and soon enough you’ve forgotten all the ”good” ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here’s a dirt simple approach, which you might have more luck with. It involves an iPhone (sorry Android friends, this is where we part ways).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Buy a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.co.uk/Mobile-Phone-Armbands/b?node=4913455031&#34;&gt;mobile phone armband&lt;/a&gt;, they’re super cheap and make you look like you know what you’re doing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set up Siri, so you can voice activate with ”Hey Siri“&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install &lt;a href=&#34;https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT205773&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/a&gt; app, then use the command ”Hey Siri, take a note”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Siri wakes up and asks you what you’d like to say&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You speak your idea and Siri creates a new note&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You carry on thinking up ideas while you run&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I told you it was simple. &lt;a href=&#34;https://harrycresswell.com/articles/intentions-2020/#keep-it-simple&#34;&gt;I like to keep it simple&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, if this worked with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.notion.so/&#34;&gt;Notion&lt;/a&gt; then we’d really be in business. I wouldn’t have to transfer notes manually and that would be awesome. Maybe that time will come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But for now, it’s a pretty good solution and a small price to pay to remember an idea which could turn into something great. Or not.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Sticking with your commitments</title>
        <link>https://azharkhan.in/articles/implementation-intentions/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 10:39:01 +0100</pubDate>
        <author>azhar932@icloud.com (Azhar Khan)</author>
        <guid>https://azharkhan.in/articles/implementation-intentions/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p class=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;
    How do you increase your chances of sticking with the things you say you’ll do? I’ve been thinking about this question a lot.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all have things we want to achieve, but staying committed and making progress towards those things can be difficult. It requires dedication – showing up day after day, investing time and energy, and continually chipping away – which isn’t exactly easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But you can make it easier by &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/JamesClear/status/1226551114935472129&#34;&gt;creating a strategy&lt;/a&gt;. A simple plan of action to help you stay committed and achieve your goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find that whenever I lean on a strategy or systematic process in my work, everything gets a whole lot easier. By planning your actions, you remove barriers preventing progress and things become autonomous. It’s no different for your long-term commitments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sticking with the things you say you’ll do is actually down to having a good strategy. And one I’ve started to use with more conscious attention is called &lt;em&gt;implementation intentions&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;implementation-intentions&#34;&gt;Implementation Intentions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In research conducted by psychologist Peter Gollwitzer on goal striving, results showed that by assigning specific situational cues to a goal – a strategy know as ”implementation intentions” – you enhance the rate of goal attainment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Implementation intentions uses something called the ”goal-specificity effect”, which shows that a person will perform better when set goals are challenging and specific, compared to those that are challenging but vague.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other words, you’re more likely to act on your intentions, &lt;em&gt;if&lt;/em&gt; you form a concrete plan involving specific situational cues. These situational cues define the &lt;em&gt;when&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;where&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; you plan to act on your intentions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peter Gollwitzer calls this an “if-then plan”; where you select an “if” cue, that’s linked to a “then” response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this idea in mind, let’s look at a few examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;implementation-intentions-in-action&#34;&gt;Implementation intentions in action&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Say your goal is to &lt;em&gt;write a book&lt;/em&gt;. To achieve your goal you might decide to &lt;em&gt;build a daily writing habit&lt;/em&gt;. Makes sense. It’s less intimidating to focus on a regular commitment, than fixating on an end goal, which feels impossible to achieve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To build your daily writing habit, you might employ an “if-then plan,” to increase your changes of staying committed and achieving your goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your ”if-then plan” may look something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If&lt;/em&gt; the time is 6 am, &lt;em&gt;then&lt;/em&gt; I will sit down to write in the study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this case, 6 am is the &lt;em&gt;cue&lt;/em&gt;, which prompts a &lt;em&gt;response&lt;/em&gt; – sitting down to write in the study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In reality this is probably over simplified. &lt;em&gt;If&lt;/em&gt; the time is 6 am &lt;em&gt;then&lt;/em&gt; your alarm would likely go off, &lt;em&gt;then&lt;/em&gt; you would wake up, &lt;em&gt;then&lt;/em&gt; sit down to write. But that’s beside the point, you get the general idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s take a look at another example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time, lets say your goal is to run a marathon. To help you schedule your training and stay committed, again, you might use an ”if-then plan”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If&lt;/em&gt; the time is 8 am, &lt;em&gt;then&lt;/em&gt; I will put on my running gear and go for a run outside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By defining the when, where, and how you want to act on your goal intentions, you affirm a concrete strategy to make your goals more attainable and your behaviour easier to stick with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now let’s look at a slightly different formula for applying implementation intentions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-simple-formula-for-implementation-intentions&#34;&gt;A simple formula for implementation intentions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In his book Atomic Habits, James Clear suggests that an implementation intention is ”a plan you make beforehand about when and where to act. That is, how you &lt;em&gt;intend to implement&lt;/em&gt; a particular habit.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;James’ formula for creating implementation intentions makes use of two of the most common cues that help trigger a habit; &lt;em&gt;time&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;location&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The formula looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will [BEHAVIOUR] at [TIME] in [LOCATION].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a simple, easy to remember way of expressing our “if-then plan”. So let’s revisit our previous example for absolute clarity, but this time apply James’ formula instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will write at 6 am in the study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this case, &lt;em&gt;write&lt;/em&gt; is our chosen behaviour. It defines &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; we will act. The time &lt;em&gt;6 am&lt;/em&gt; specifies ‘when’ we will act. And &lt;em&gt;the study&lt;/em&gt; provides a location. It clarifies ’where’ we will act.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I like most about James’ formula is that it makes it so simple and clear. It literally spells it out for you and makes your commitment feel so easy to accomplish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But ‘feeling easy’ isn’t exactly a great explanation for why implementation intentions work. So now, let’s put these fomulas to one side, and talk about at what make this strategy such a powerful tool for goal attainment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-implementation-intentions-work&#34;&gt;Why implementation intentions work&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By defining a concrete plan of when, where, and how to act, you improve your mental representation of a situation, making it highly active and accessible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other words, by using cues to trigger your actions, you improve your perception, attention and memory concerning the situation. You create a strong associative link between a cue and the response, making your behaviour more likely to occur in the given situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This associative link helps make your behaviour automatic and you begin to perform your actions with very little conscious effort. Your behaviour becomes subconscious, making it easier to show up and practice often.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without the need for decision making about your next actions, you’re left with plenty of energy for what really matters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;keep-in-mind&#34;&gt;Keep in mind&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goal attainment is down to having a good strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creating situational cues – for when and where you will act – improves your chances of sticking with your commitments and reaching your goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assigning specific cues to a chosen behaviour, creates clarity in your mind and a concrete plan of action. This is a strategy know as &lt;em&gt;implementation intentions&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having a concrete plan for your commitments makes your decisions more autonomous. You spend less time thinking about your actions or fixating on the end goal, and more time being productive. You make things easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;further-reading&#34;&gt;Further reading&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://psych.nyu.edu/oettingen/Gollwitzer,%20P.%20M.,%20&amp;amp;%20Oettingen,%20G.%20%282013%29.%20In%20%20M.%20Gellman%20&amp;amp;%20J.%20R.%20Turner%20%28Eds.%29.pdf&#34;&gt;Implementation Intentions&lt;/a&gt;, Peter M. Gollwitzer and Gabriele Oettingen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jamesclear.com/implementation-intentions&#34;&gt;Achieve Your Goals&lt;/a&gt; from James Clear&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://daringtolivefully.com/implementation-intentions&#34;&gt;The Key To Goal Success&lt;/a&gt; by Marelisa Fabrega&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thinkinglifter.com/implementation-intentions/&#34;&gt;Implementation Intentions: How to Get Consistent Results&lt;/a&gt; Philip Stefanov&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>What can we learn from shortcuts?</title>
        <link>https://azharkhan.in/notes/what-can-we-learn-from-shortcuts/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 23:25:36 +0100</pubDate>
        <author>azhar932@icloud.com (Azhar Khan)</author>
        <guid>https://azharkhan.in/notes/what-can-we-learn-from-shortcuts/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;These are my notes from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ted.com/talks/tom_hulme_what_can_we_learn_from_shortcuts&#34;&gt;What can we learn from shortcuts&lt;/a&gt;, a TED Talk by designer and Google Ventures Partner &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/thulme&#34;&gt;Tom Hulme&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Empathy for what your customers want is the biggest leading indicator of business success“&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do you build a product people really want? Allow consumers to be a part of the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shortcuts are desire paths — often the path of least resistance.
The point where design and user experience diverge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;applying-this-to-launching-products&#34;&gt;Applying this to launching products&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Design for a real need at low friction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People are resourceful, they will always find the low friction routes, to save money and time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Observing the user behaviour will help you design better products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Co-design with the user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Launch and learn. Launching early will teach you what people really want. It’s an efficient way of spotting desire paths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The worlds in flux, respond to changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watch for desire paths to emerge, then take the appropriate action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Design for real life: for real human needs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Empathy for what your customers want is the biggest leading indicator of business success&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Design in low friction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;launch and learn: The answer is out there, not inside the building. Observer users behaviour to find out what they really want&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;stay responsive: respond to change&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Smartcuts</title>
        <link>https://azharkhan.in/notes/smartcuts/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2016 21:34:41 +0100</pubDate>
        <author>azhar932@icloud.com (Azhar Khan)</author>
        <guid>https://azharkhan.in/notes/smartcuts/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Notes taken from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/20910174-smartcuts?from_search=true&#34;&gt;Smartcuts: How Hackers, Innovators, and Icons Accelerate Success&lt;/a&gt; by Shane Snow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whereas by dictionary definition shortcuts can be amoral, you can think of smartcuts as shortcuts with integrity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abagnale took shortcuts and regretted it. Franklin used smartcuts and got his face on a $100 bill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m convinced that true success has more to do with our becoming better people and building a better world while we do these things than it does with the size of our bank accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I see this book as a simultaneous hat tip and counterpoint to some of the great success and innovation literature out there (check out shanesnow.com/booklist for my recommendations). It’s a re-analysis and first codification of the ways rapid success has happened throughout history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;patterns of lateral thinking (smartcuts)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The players eliminated resistance by breaking the big challenge (acquire something valuable like a TV) into a series of easier, repeatable challenges (make a tiny trade).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Startups that pivot once or twice raise 2.5x more money, have 3.6x better user growth, and are 52% less likely to scale prematurely.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mentorship is the secret of many of the highest-profile achievers throughout history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sam Walton, founder of Walmart, studied and stole moves from master retailers fabulously well. He openly admitted it. “Most everything I’ve done, I’ve copied from someone else,” he said. The problem is that two people can study the same business model, watch the same video, or even take the same advice from a mentor, and one person might pick up critical details that the other misses. The late literary giant Saul Bellow would call someone with the ability to spot important details among noise a “first-class noticer.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oscar Wilde once said, “Experience is the name everyone gives to their mistakes.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If you’re not failing you are either very lucky, very good, or not pushing the boundaries enough,” Staats says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All great successes make mistakes along the way. NBA star Michael Jordan missed more than 9,000 shots and lost 300 games in his career. He was the best, and he failed a lot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crucially, experts tended to be able to turn off the part of their egos that took legitimate feedback personally when it came to their craft, and they were confident enough to parse helpful feedback from incorrect feedback. Meanwhile novices psyched themselves out. They needed encouragement and feared failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tough part about negative feedback is in separating ourselves from the perceived failure and turning our experiences into objective experiments. But when we do that, feedback becomes much more powerful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They know, because they got the feedback early, and often. “Speed is an essential part of our game,” Leonard explains. “The rapid feedback . . . it’s non-stop.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an age of platforms, creative problem solving is more valuable than computational skill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the saying, attributed to Dr. Seuss, goes: “It is better to know how to learn than to know.”*&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You can build on top of a lot of things that exist in this world,” David Heinemeier Hansson told me. “Somebody goes in and does that hard, ground level science based work. “And then on top of that,” he smiles, “you build the art.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best way to be in the water when the wave comes is to budget time for swimming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grant would know. He wrote the book on the subject. In his bestseller, Give and Take, he presents rigorous research showing that a disproportionate number of the most successful people in a given industry are extremely generous. From medical students to engineers to salespeople, his studies find givers at the top of the ladder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The number one problem with networking is people are out for themselves,” says Scott Gerber, founder of the Young Entrepreneur Council, who coined the term superconnector.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Superconnecting is about learning what people need, then talking about ‘how do we create something of value.’”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No matter the medium or method, giving is the timeless smartcut for harnessing superconnectors and creating serendipity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Design for Extreme Affordability,” or how to create products for people who live on less than a dollar a&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Innovation is about doing something differently, rather than creating something from nothing (invention) or doing the same thing better (improvement).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key feature of disruptively innovative products is cost savings (either time or money). But the key ingredient behind the scenes of every disruptive product is simplification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like Holmes, hackers strip the unnecessary from their lives. They zero in on what matters. Like great writers, innovators have the fortitude to cut the adverbs. This is why Apple founder Steve Jobs’s closet was filled with dozens of identical black turtlenecks and Levi’s 501 jeans—to simplify his choices. US presidents do the same thing. “You’ll see I wear only gray or blue suits,” President Barack Obama told Michael Lewis for his October 2012 Vanity Fair cover story. “I don’t want to make decisions about what I’m eating or wearing. Because I have too many other decisions to make.” I don’t want to make decisions about what I’m eating or wearing? How could that possibly make one better at governing? Or problem solving? And isn’t variety the very spice of life? What about creativity? Or not going crazy? What he’s talking about has been proven in experiments led by Dr. Kathleen Vohs of the University of Minnesota, experiments that show that making lots of tiny choices depletes one’s subsequent self-control. Students who were forced to decide between products for long periods of time had significantly less willpower afterward than classmates who answered random questions instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notes: 1) understanding minimalism&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apparently, patience and willpower, even creativity, are exhaustible resources. That’s why so many busy and powerful people practice mind-clearing meditation and stick to rigid daily routines: to minimize distractions and maximize good decision making.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, Apple’s iPod won the MP3 player war with breakthrough simplicity, both in physical design and how the company explained it. While other companies touted “4 Gigabytes and a 0.5 Gigahertz processor!” Apple simply said, “1,000 songs in your pocket.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creativity comes easier within constraints&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;as Musk likes to say, “The first step is to establish that something is possible; then probability will occur.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Generally speaking, if you’re gonna make something ten percent better than the way things currently are, you better be great in sales and marketing, because you’re gonna have to talk people into changing their behavior for a very marginal increase in value,” explains Astro Teller.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If, on the other hand, you make something ten times better for a large number of people—you really produce huge amounts of new value—the money’s gonna come find you. Because it would be hard not to make money if you’re really adding that much value.” This is exactly&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Big causes attract big believers, big investors, big capital, big-name advisers, and big talent. They force us to rethink convention and hack the ladder of success. To engage with masters and to leverage waves and platforms and superconnectors. To swing and to simplify, to quickly turn failure into feedback. To become not just bigger, but truly better. And they remind us, once again, that together we can achieve the implausible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a first-class noticer, a master of tiny details about how shoes are put together and how consumers on the street think about them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was in the water before the wave came.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>