<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Booknotes on Azhar Khan</title>
    <link>https://azharkhan.in/tags/booknotes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Booknotes on Azhar Khan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>azhar932@icloud.com (Azhar Khan)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>azhar932@icloud.com (Azhar Khan)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2016 21:34:41 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://azharkhan.in/tags/booknotes/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Content Machine</title>
        <link>https://azharkhan.in/notes/content-machine/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2016 21:34:41 +0100</pubDate>
        <author>azhar932@icloud.com (Azhar Khan)</author>
        <guid>https://azharkhan.in/notes/content-machine/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Notes taken from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/36603232-content-machine?from_search=true&#34;&gt;Content Machine&lt;/a&gt; by Dan Norris.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no point at all in generating mediocre content. Don’t just write about your business or your product. Your content has to be educational and solve problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talk to potential customers and figure out what they want. Throw away everything you learned in school. Writing content is a two-way conversation, not a speech. Be personal and make people feel like you are there with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quality Over Quantity&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I loved creating the content, but there was a problem. I measured myself based on how much content I created, not how much traction that content got. The quantity, not the quality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;eventually worked out that one spectacularly successful piece of content was infinitely more valuable than 100 pieces of content that go unnoticed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Content marketing is releasing something interesting that grabs attention for a business and builds trust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most important pieces of the content marketing definition are attention and trust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You want to put out content that helps people, gets them to pay attention to you and your business, and, over time, garners their trust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These people become part of your community, they help promote your content, refer people to your business, and may even become partners or customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You have assumed that your job is to create content, when really your job is to market a business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creating great content is not enough, because without a great business, you are sending attention to something that is broken (or non-existent).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10 Characteristics Of A High-Growth Business&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If these are not present in your business, you will struggle to make any form of marketing work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are going to focus on building a content machine, you need something that will grow without your constant attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They Are Fundamentally Profitable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the profit margin in your business is set so you are unable to replace yourself and still make a profit, then you are in trouble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s a very simple calculation I recommend every business owner should perform: Figure out everything that goes into serving a customer. How many hours will you need from X, Y, and Z staff members to complete the tasks, and how much do those staff members cost. Imagine your business is at a reasonable size, and that you have all of the tools and technologies necessary to manage a decent number of clients. Distribute the costs across those clients to come up with a rough idea of how much it’s going to cost to deliver your service. Take that number and, at the very least, double it. That is your price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They Operate In A Large Market&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Common business advice tells you to find a small niche and go after it. I don’t like this advice, and I don’t see successful high-growth companies doing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being in a large market has resulted in constant, high, and at times almost unmanageable growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notes: 1) large market means bigger reach, so leads to more growth, also allows  for more varied content&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They Naturally Build Assets Over Time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All high-growth companies have some sort of assets that set them apart from their competition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They Have a Simple, Relatable Differentiator&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;high-growth companies tend to go after existing problems, and they solve them with a unique twist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some examples: WP Curve: Like a developer except unlimited fixes 24/7.  Uber: Like taxis except cleaner, safer, cheaper, nice smelling, and they actually arrive.  Airbnb: Like hotels except you get more for less.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;5&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They Focus On Growing Consistent Revenue At a High Lifetime Value&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Businesses that are successful in the long term generally have a predictable revenue model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can invest in tools, technology, and people that you need to grow, because you are confident you will be able to afford it next month. You can say “no” to certain customers or projects, because you already have a good solid base of revenue. You can accurately estimate your profit margin and your cashflow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building a business by selling a one off $20 product is going to be a lot tougher than a business that sells an $80 monthly subscription.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;lifetime value,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;6&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They Invest In A Memorable Brand&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They Are Started By A Team, Not An Individual&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s extremely rare for a decent company to be built by an individual and not a founding team. Just look at the startup world for guidance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like every entrepreneur, I tend to think I can do everything and am “a jack of all trades”. But I had zero success until I started businesses with other people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;8&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They Know How To Say “No,” And They Do It Often&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great businesses choose what they are going to do, and they do it extremely well. It takes a long time, generally a lot of people, and a lot of money to truly achieve “world class” status. If your business has multiple focuses rather than one main task, it might be a sign that you are in trouble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn how to say “no”. Instead, reach “world class” status at one thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;9&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They Understand The Power Of Monthly Growth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t think so much about how much money you will make in a year. Think about how much you will grow every single month, and before you know it your business will be significantly bigger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;10&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They Think “Long Term”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great businesses avoid get-rich-quick schemes and over-optimization. They focus on solid, long-term strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting in the press, building a public profile, putting out useful content, fostering important relationships, and developing a great company culture are all examples of solid long-term strategies. These aren’t going to result in quick wins, but they are what creates great companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monetization Logic&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monetization logic is a simple “Yeah that makes sense” test that is often missing from people’s content marketing efforts. The easiest way to determine whether it exists is to ask the question, “Does it make sense that someone would consume this content and then go on to become a customer?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There needs to be a logical link between your content, your audience, and whatever it is you are selling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Content marketing, by its nature, is a long-term exercise. Most top blogs create content for months or years before they hit traction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Content marketing is about building trust, and you can’t build trust overnight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;work.  It takes a while for some channels to kick in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It takes a long time to endear a valuable community member.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It takes time to find your place. I’ve mentioned how critical it is to work out your core vision and work out what your audience loves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good content breeds more good content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember, you don’t want to spit out just any content at a rapid speed. You want to do it with direction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 10-Minute Content Strategy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You need to define a strategy and then build processes around that strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve included a free ten-minute content marketing strategy template at &lt;a href=&#34;http://contentmachine.com/resources&#34;&gt;http://contentmachine.com/resources&lt;/a&gt; for you to work through. Here are the components:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vision – What is your blog about when it reaches its full potential?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Values – What are the key values that will inform your content choices?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inspirations – Where do you look for inspiration (design, content, voice, etc.)?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Strategy Comment – Do you have a high-level description of the overall strategy behind the blog?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Target Communities – What groups of people are you creating content for, and where do they hang out?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Differentiators – How will this blog be different from what is already available?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfair Advantage – What about you, your business, your style, your team, etc. gives you an advantage?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key Relationships – Who are the big influencers capable of boosting your content&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are struggling, check out Followerwonk or Little Bird.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Metrics – How will you know when your content is successful? If in doubt, use my three key metrics of total shares, comments, and email replies (more on these later).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lead Magnets and CTAs (Calls to Action) – What items can you use to encourage people to opt in, and what will your CTA be?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your Content Vision&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s going to be very hard to make a content marketing strategy work if you aren’t clear on the end game. A good way to think about your vision is answering the question, “What will I/we stand for?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Often they didn’t agree, and they left passionate replies to that effect. But they were interested. They were engaged. Radical transparency became a theme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Giving away detailed processes or tools that have helped us grow is another important factor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the vision for your content? What will separate it from others in your industry? What do you believe will influence your content strategy?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;people aren’t simply writing blog posts. They have defined a community to help, and they are executing on a broad vision. They believe something about what people want and aren’t currently getting. And they are using their unique advantage to fill that gap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two ways to define who you are creating content for. One is to come up with a “Customer Avatar” that describes exactly who your ideal customer is, what their wants and needs are, and what they are looking for in your content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your ideal customers will hear about you over a long period of time, through multiple sources, and that is how trust is built.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;way to define who you are creating content for—is to choose a community and help them with what they need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t be picky about whether each piece of content is generating leads. Just create as much value as you can for the most amount of people in your chosen community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Give away as many useful things as you can, create content that people can really relate to, and if possible, offer a unique perspective that people haven’t come across before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great content is something you provide to your audience that captures their attention and encourages them to engage and share.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lessons Learned From Bad And Good Content&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since poor quality is one of the top causes of failed content, there is one question you have to keep coming back to: Is my content actually good?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t Be Afraid To Go Outside Your Niche&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creating niche-specific content is the easy option, and it will be the first thing your competitors do. Get the jump on them by going outside this content to more interesting topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Care About Your Community&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask them what their problems are and what they need help with. Ask them what other sites they like and pay attention to what they share.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be More Generous&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Content marketing is a trust-building exercise, so the more generosity the better. In the next chapter, I will tell you about how I was inspired by Noah Kagan’s appearance on the Smart Passive Income Podcast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be More Transparent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being transparent is a natural trust builder. Transparency in business has become a trend of late, and it’s a trend I have been very keen to embrace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;5&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be More Contrarian&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Offering a contrarian view got me a lot of attention. At the time of release the only startup book outranking it on Amazon was Zero To One, a book about how to build a business by being contrarian.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not essential that all of your content disagrees with everyone. It’s just one way to get noticed,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thought leaders like Tony Robbins and Seth Godin use this technique all the time. “Most people think X, but actually…” If you are one of the people that think X, then you certainly need to pay attention to why Tony thinks you are wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;6&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be More Actionable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;someone can take what you have produced and use it in their life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a list of top ten mistakes to avoid when writing a sales letter is interesting. An actual sales letter template which walks people through how to structure their own sales letter is truly actionable, because people can take it and use it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s why I’ve included lots of frameworks in this book. The book itself might be interesting, but I want you to take action on the information. The frameworks enable you to do that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you can create content that is legitimately actionable, it will get consumed more, shared more, and it will convert more readers to active community members or eventually customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think about how people will use your content and what you can do to make it more likely that they will actually use it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;7&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tell A Better Story&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Storytelling is a great way to capture and hold people’s attention. It’s been proven over generations and is a simple strategy for you to use with your content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have a look at this line chart that represents the story of Cinderella as designed by Kurt Vonnegut. 2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn about storytelling models that would work for your topic areas and figure out a way to tell your story in a way that people can relate to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generating Content Topics (The Twenty Topics Framework)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with finding topics. These are the broad areas you will cover in your content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This framework is available as a downloadable resource at &lt;a href=&#34;http://contentmachine.com/resources&#34;&gt;http://contentmachine.com/resources&lt;/a&gt;. It’s a Google Doc that you can use to build a list of your own ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understand And Leverage Your Strengths&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What works for me is to experiment with what resonates with my audience, what I can do well, and what I can do consistently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m writing this book on a plane. The guy next to me is watching a movie (hopefully he’s not reading this). The guy in front is listening to music. The people behind me are sleeping. It’s lunchtime on a Monday, but I don’t want to be watching movies, listening to music, or sleeping—I want to be writing. So, I’m writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever you enjoy, if you can point yourself in a direction that creates something useful for your community, then you are well on your way to creating good content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Content Quality Standards&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Useful Would someone actually use this? Write to solve an issue or pain point for a community of people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Easy To Read Ensure that your audience doesn&amp;rsquo;t struggle to read your content. Have short intros, simple language, lots of white space, and eliminate fluffy language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Has Credibility Extra credibility helps. How else can you add credibility to this content? If the author has credibility to start with, that is great. Having opinions from experts included in the article is another way. Data and links from external sources is another way. Great design and high-quality writing is another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emotionally Relatable&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write stories that will appeal to their emotions. What images and words can you use that will grab them?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s Not All About You&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some content about you can work well, but generally it should be about the reader. Look for more “you’s” than “I’s”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be Specific, Not General Broad, general content is rarely useful. Be as specific as you can and use active language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be Generous Look at your content and make a call on its motives&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be Original&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make It Shareable Create the type of content people would share and tell others about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interesting Remember, if it’s not interesting, it’s not content marketing. Is the headline eye-catching?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;High-Quality Design&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flow Does the content follow a logical structure that draws readers from one section to the next? It should be easy to read from section to section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Entertaining&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long I have found that long and detailed content works well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monitoring Traction Of course, just paying attention to what you want isn’t a recipe for success. In the end, it’s your audience that matters. You need to look at what content is resonating with them and find the sweet spot between what you are good at and what the audience loves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a “Like” is a sign that the content wasn’t good enough to share.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;recommend paying attention to three key metrics. Shares Rather than focusing on visits or likes, I suggest looking at social media shares.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“liking” it is great, but actually sharing is a whole new level. Only the best content gets shared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To work out total shares you can add buttons to your site or use Like Explorer or BuzzSumo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Email Replies We have an email list we’ve built up over the years, and each week we send out our best content&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These come directly from my email address, and the replies tell me what is really resonating with people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over time you will get a clear picture of what content works best for your audience. This will then feed back into your content strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Content Driven SEO&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I do agree that SEO is important, I think high-quality content is more important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ignore the so-called “experts” who say they have a “secret” to ranking well in Google. In my experience, trying to outsmart Google is not the answer for long-term, sustainable traffic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t Screw Up The Basic On-Page SEO Factors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sure your theme is using the right tags in the right places&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create Lots of High-Quality Content&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do Basic Keyword Research When Needed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;put in a broad keyword for what I want to write about, and then I’ll choose a keyword that people are actually searching for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optimize The Post For The Keyword&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sure your keyword is used in your post title. This, in turn, will ensure it appears in your heading tags, any auto generated internal links, and your page URL&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mention the keyword in your first paragraph. Usually this is pretty easy, and you would do it anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sure your SEO title (sometimes the same as your post title) includes your keyword and is the right length, and you have a description that includes your keyword and entices the user to click through from Google.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People share and link to high-quality content. This is what Google loves, and that will never change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They don’t simply create content. They create content for a certain community of people, and they do it better with a unique angle so they get noticed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are also some logistical things you’d have to consider: Do you need to hire virtual assistants to help with the core part of the work?  Can you hire someone to ghostwrite or guest write the content?  Will you get your team to help?  Will you utilize external services for part of the process or hire a remote team?  What is your plan for when you are sick or you are away—can you stack the content up?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are going to do the daily thing, you can create the posts in WordPress and use the scheduler to publish them in the future. A lot of the steps required to help with this level of content production can be managed by a Virtual Assistant for $400-$500 a month, full time. Check out Virtual Staff Finder if you want to go down this path.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Giver Noah Kagan is a guy I could have featured in a few of these chapters. Noah really shines in his approach to how much he gives away. Ultimately, content marketing is about creating value for a community of people. The more you can give away, the more you are going to stand out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;first noticed the extreme nature of Noah’s giver mentality on his interview 1 with Pat Flynn on Smart Passive Income.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He started releasing his own plugins under the SumoMe brand. At first a Twitter highlighter tool, then a heat maps tool, then a pop-up tool, then a content marketing analytics tool—all for free. All that on top of regular high-quality, detailed posts via his blog OK Dork&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How To Be A Giver&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use Schedule Once, so people can easily book times directly in my calendar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Email courses on helpful topics.  Video training on YouTube or sites like Udemy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Analyst&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gathering and reporting on original data is one of the best ways to build a content marketing strategy. Why? Because it’s automatically differentiated. It’s difficult, if not impossible, for competitors to report on the same data as you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some companies gather and report on data based on information they are already collecting. Some undertake dedicated surveys to produce unique content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How To Be An Analyst&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use a survey tool like TypeForm or Google Forms to build and send out a survey. We used TypeForm, because it creates great-looking surveys and looks very professional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create a SlideShare summary of the result for sharing and a full PDF report for your site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How To Be A Comedian&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marie Forleo is a great example. She has built a business education empire by delivering serious messages in a fun and quirky way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David Nihil, author of Do You Talk Funny: 7 Comedy Habits to Become a Better (and Funnier) Public Speaker,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;his business, FunnyBizz, offers a service that specifically rewrites blogs posts and makes them funnier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some of David’s tips: Tell a story in a relatable way, include something broad that people can specifically relate to (maybe local references), then bring it back to something that happened to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Set the scene. Write as if you are describing something to a blind person, and be very specific with detail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use emotive or funny words like “weird”, “crazy”, or “nuts”, and be passionate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use present tense—“I&amp;rsquo;m walking and I see” rather than “I was walking and I saw”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use the rule of three to create memorable content. Build tension and surprise with items one and two and something unexpected with three.  Add a callback at the end to tie it together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the safest humor involves personal stories, because they are guaranteed to be original and can be easily practiced and perfected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;specific structure for making stories funny: Identity – Who are you; set the scene; who are you with; how are you feeling?  Struggle – What are you struggling with?  Discovery – What was your big discovery?  Surprise – What is a surprising twist that no one is expecting?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google AdWords Keyword Planner Visit the Google AdWords Keyword Planner.  Enter some keywords that describe the sort of content you want to create—for example, I’ll enter “Craft Beer” if I am working on Black Hops Brewing.  Click “Get ideas”.  Click the “Keyword Ideas” tab to just see the individual keyword ideas.  Use the “Keyword Filters” on the left to only show keywords with a certain amount of searches. I generally look for keywords with between 200-500 searches for a new site, or more for an established site. In the example above I can see quite a few keywords in the 1,000-2,000 searches range, including keywords like “brewing equipment”, “homebrew recipes”, “best craft beers”, and “craft beer festival”. All of these would make a good starting point for some content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Podcast – Grab some other industry experts and jump on Skype to chat about what is happening in the industry. Use Pamela for Skype or Ecamm Call Recorder to record the call, publish it on your blog, and submit the feed to iTunes. I have a podcasting guide linked up at &lt;a href=&#34;http://contentmachine.com/resources&#34;&gt;http://contentmachine.com/resources&lt;/a&gt; that will help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Video – Do the same thing as Podcasts, but use Google Hangouts or YouTube Live and publish the video to YouTube.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How To Be An Artist Utilizing the power of images could mean adding some images to existing content, or it could mean creating brand new, image-heavy content. Here are eleven ways you can go about ramping up your image content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Screenshots&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Skitch and Jing are great tools for creating screenshots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;5&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Screenshares, Webinars, And Video Courses If you have an educational focus for your content, screenshares and videos are a great way to get the learning across.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All you need to create a decent screenshare video is a USB headset and screen capture software like Camtasia or ScreenFlow&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marie Forleo is a great place to get inspiration when it comes to doing online videos well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are three main ways to create an infographic: Use an infographic builder like Visme or Piktochart&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;10&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Animated GIFs Animated GIFs and autoplay videos stand out as a big trend at the moment. GIFs are being used regularly on websites now for things like showing you how to use software.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GifGrabber is a simple tool for putting together animated GIFs for software usage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chapter 5: Scale: Building The Machine&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Defining Your Funnel&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A funnel is a way to transition the broad members of the community down to a smaller group of customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s no “one size fits all”, but I’ve found three popular options that work well. The email funnel  The product funnel  The content funnel&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to look at this strategy, SumoMe, OptimizePress, and LeadPages are the two leading tools for building email opt ins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Product Funnel The product funnel is where the main call to action on the site is using your product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Content Funnel The content funnel is my personal preference. It aims to build an email list, but it also favours content and brand over email opt ins. It requires you to create a lot of content,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We put most of our content out in blog posts freely available on our site. Sometimes we’ll support those blog posts with Google Docs, frameworks, ebooks, and downloads that keen readers can grab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With larger projects where trust is a must, we’ll just give it all away publicly with no email opt in. That is what I do with my books. All of the frameworks, downloads, and resources for this book are freely available at &lt;a href=&#34;http://contentmachine.com/resources&#34;&gt;http://contentmachine.com/resources&lt;/a&gt;. This builds trust, and people are more likely to get behind the project and share it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Relevant Lead Magnets&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, it takes a bit of effort to add a different opt in to every post—not to mention setting up the website and email sequences to support providing the lead magnet. I think the best way to do this is by checking your top posts and making sure all of them have post-specific lead magnets. If you don’t have many posts just yet, you can go on gut feeling and add them to the posts you think will be winners. If you’ve built up a good library of content, I’d suggest automating this with Zapier:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The basic idea here is to use the “Schedule” zap to automatically create a task for your admin team. I have a team of Virtual Assistants in the Philippines who look after these things for me. I use Trello to manage our tasks, but Zapier integrates with lots of different tools if you aren’t a Trello user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;every month the admin team is reminded to look in Google Analytics under Behaviour/Site content at a year’s worth of data to see the top 25 posts. They manually check through each post to see if there is a post-specific opt in at the end. If&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Five Must-Have Sequences For Content Marketers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Content Drip Or Weekly Email&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A content drip sequence is a series of pre-written emails that will send out useful content to the person on a set schedule.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal is to build trust and build up desire for your product/service at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Content Suggestion Sequence&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like to have one simple email that gets sent to subscribers asking them what they would like to hear about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are using content in your business and you want it to get traction, you need to learn what people want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you let people reply to your emails, then you actually read and reply back, you will build a legion of close fans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If they suggested something you hadn’t thought of, then add it to your ideas list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pitch Sequence&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To ensure I’m not pitching the same people over and over again, I like to have a pitch sequence. I use Infusionsoft, which makes this sort of thing pretty easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are a few tools you might want to use to help with this step: Inkybee is a tool for reaching out to other influence content creators in your niche.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inkybee is a tool for reaching out to other influence content creators in your niche.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Editing Notes Here we generate practical editing notes and list other things to look out for. Examples could include: When reviewing after first draft, keep an eye out for: Filler words like: I think, etc, things, stuff.  Long sentences with no punctuation.  Long paragraphs that aren’t broken up.  Waffling or off-topic sentences.  Double check links.  Make sure links work.  Make sure they open in a new tab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Put this information in a separate document with your final article. SEO Meta description (less than 156 chars).  Focus Keyword.  Post Tags.  A link to a dropbox folder with your images.  Please save your blog post images in this folder in the dimensions listed below.  Include a featured image.  Include a large photo of yourself to use for social sharing (we’ll put a quote from the post on the photo).  Title of each image.  Name the image with keywords spaced with underscores (Monthy_Income_Chart).  A brief, two-sentence excerpt to entice readers.  One or two tweetable quotes from your post.  An author bio if this is your first submission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Content Promotion&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I find works is a simple procedure that an admin person or virtual assistant can follow and apply to all content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lead Magnets If you think it’s going to be a popular piece of content, you might want to make a post-specific opt in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check The Retargeting Funnel Category Remember the retargeting funnel. If you’ve set it up properly, it will automatically retarget people with ads and emails if you post content in certain categories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mentions Tweets If we have mentioned someone in the article, we want to draft some “mentions tweets”. Log into your Twitter client of choice (I’d suggest Twitter itself, or Hootsuite or Buffer) and schedule tweets with three people per tweet like: Mentions in [post name] on [main topic] [@guest1] [@guest2] and [@guest3] [link]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scheduled Tweets We also schedule a bunch of tweets for each piece of content. We come up with a few different tweets based on the content and manually post them at intervals after the content is published. We use Hootsuite to schedule the tweets, but you can also use Buffer to auto-schedule them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be Part Of The 5% That Gets Shit Done&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve noticed one common trait in every successful entrepreneur I know. It’s something I don’t see in the rest of the population, and it’s what makes them entrepreneurs. It’s their relentless focus on delivering something. Getting shit done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ninety-five percent of people will happily read a book, maybe even take notes, but they don’t measure themselves based on what they deliver. They won’t change anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Five percent of people do. They are the entrepreneurs. It’s not enough for them to read a book. It only matters when they deliver something as a result. Maybe it’s implementing a new content strategy, testing out a new type of article, or brainstorming some new ideas for their blog.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Eating Animals</title>
        <link>https://azharkhan.in/notes/eating-animals/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2016 21:34:41 +0100</pubDate>
        <author>azhar932@icloud.com (Azhar Khan)</author>
        <guid>https://azharkhan.in/notes/eating-animals/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Thoughts and notes taken from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/6604712-eating-animals?from_search=true&#34;&gt;Eating Animals&lt;/a&gt; by Jonathan Safran Foer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;thoughts&#34;&gt;Thoughts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A real eye opener on the factory faming industry. This book will make you seriously consider your meet consumption. If not for ethical or environmental reasons then perhaps for the benefit of your health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Food serves two parallel purposes: it nourishes and it helps you remember.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is something about eating animals that tends to polarize: never eat them or never sincerely question eating them; become an activist or disdain activists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It raises significant philosophical questions and is a $140 billion–plus a year industry that occupies nearly a third of the land on the planet, shapes ocean ecosystems, and may well determine the future of earth’s climate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have waged war, or rather let a war be waged, against all of the animals we eat. This war is new and has a name: factory farming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than any set of practices, factory farming is a mind-set: reduce production costs to the absolute minimum and systematically ignore or “externalize” such costs as environmental degradation, human disease, and animal suffering. For thousands of years, farmers took their cues from natural processes. Factory farming considers nature an obstacle to be overcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Children confront us with our paradoxes and hypocrisies, and we are exposed. You need to find an answer for every why—Why do we do this? Why don’t we do that?—and often there isn’t a good one. So you say, simply, because.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;blockquote class=&#34;PullQuote PullQuote--right&#34;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
            Animal agriculture makes a 40% greater contribution to global warming than all transportation in the world combined; it is the number one cause of climate change.
            
            
        &lt;/p&gt;
        
            &lt;figcaption&gt;&amp;mdash; Jonathan Safran Foer&lt;/figcaption&gt;
        
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chickens once had a life expectancy of fifteen to twenty years, but the modern broiler is typically killed at around six weeks. Their daily growth rate has increased roughly 400 percent.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The average shrimp-trawling operation throws 80 to 90 percent of the sea animals it captures overboard, dead or dying, as bycatch. (Endangered species amount to much of this bycatch.) Shrimp account for only 2 percent of global seafood by weight, but shrimp trawling accounts for 33 percent of global bycatch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cruelty depends on an understanding of cruelty, and the ability to choose against it. Or to choose to ignore it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How much do I value creating a socially comfortable situation, and how much do I value acting socially responsible?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the livestock sector is responsible for 18 percent of greenhouse gas emissions, around 40 percent more than the entire transport sector—&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;omnivores contribute seven times the volume of greenhouse gases that vegans do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Animal agriculture] should be a major policy focus when dealing with problems of land degradation, climate change and air pollution, water shortage and water pollution and loss of biodiversity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We live in a world in which it’s conventional to treat an animal like a hunk of wood and extreme to treat an animal like an animal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No one fired a pistol to mark the start of the race to the bottom. The earth just tilted and everyone slid into the hole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What the industry figured out—and this was the real revolution—is that you don’t need healthy animals to make a profit. Sick animals are more profitable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The highest rates of osteoporosis are seen in countries where people consume the most dairy foods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The entire goliath of the food industry is ultimately driven and determined by the choices we make as the waiter gets impatient for our order or in the practicalities and whimsies of what we load into our shopping carts or farmers’-market bags.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is the reason the factory farm system is failing and won’t work over the long term: it’s created a food industry whose primary concern isn’t feeding people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At one level, this is the result of the normal process of corporations pursuing profit by making sure they have access to resources their competitors don’t. There is, obviously, a lot of money at stake here: billions of dollars, which could either be spread among a handful of megacorporations or among hundreds of thousands of small farmers. But&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The factory farm has succeeded by divorcing people from their food, eliminating farmers, and ruling agriculture by corporate fiat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just how destructive does a culinary preference have to be before we decide to eat something else? If contributing to the suffering of billions of animals that live miserable lives and (quite often) die in horrific ways isn’t motivating, what would be? If being the number one contributor to the most serious threat facing the planet (global warming) isn’t enough, what is? And if you are tempted to put off these questions of conscience, to say not now, then when?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day, factory farming isn’t about feeding people; it’s about money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If animal agriculture has become a joke, perhaps this is the punch line: even Bill Niman has said he would no longer eat Niman Ranch beef.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not in the end a complicated position. Nor is it a veiled argument for vegetarianism. It is an argument for vegetarianism, but it’s also an argument for another, wiser animal agriculture and more honorable omnivory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not in the end a complicated position. Nor is it a veiled argument for vegetarianism. It is an argument for vegetarianism, but it’s also an argument for another, wiser animal agriculture and more honorable omnivory. If we are not given the option to live without violence, we are given the choice to center our meals around harvest or slaughter, husbandry or war. We have chosen slaughter. We have chosen war. That’s the truest version of our story of eating animals. Can we tell a new story?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The three years I spent writing this book, for example, saw the first documentation that livestock contribute more to global warming than anything else; saw the first major research institution (the Pew Commission) recommend the total phaseout of multiple dominant intensive-confinement practices; saw the first state (Colorado) illegalize common factory farm practices (gestation and veal crates) as a result of negotiations with industry (rather than campaigns against industry); saw the first supermarket chain of any kind (Whole Foods) commit to a systematic and extensive program of animal welfare labeling; and saw the first major national newspaper (the New York Times) editorialize against factory farming as a whole, arguing that “animal husbandry has been turned into animal abuse,” and “manure… has been turned into toxic waste.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve restricted myself to mostly discussing how our food choices affect the ecology of our planet and the lives of its animals, but I could have just as easily made the entire book about public health, workers’ rights, decaying rural communities, or global poverty—all of which are profoundly affected by factory farming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To accept the factory farm feels inhuman. To accept the factory farm—to feed the food it produces to my family, to support it with my money—would make me less myself, less my grandmother’s grandson, less my son’s father. This is what my grandmother meant when she said, “If nothing matters, there’s nothing to save.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Everybody Writes</title>
        <link>https://azharkhan.in/notes/everybody-writes/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2016 21:34:41 +0100</pubDate>
        <author>azhar932@icloud.com (Azhar Khan)</author>
        <guid>https://azharkhan.in/notes/everybody-writes/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Notes taken from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/23001125-everybody-writes&#34;&gt;Everybody Writes&lt;/a&gt; by Ann Handley&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note to self&lt;/strong&gt;: Look into &lt;em&gt;“The Elements of Style by Strunk and White”&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;On Writing by Stephen King&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing well is part habit, part knowledge of some fundamental rules, and part giving a damn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Choose words well, and write with economy and style and honest empathy for your reader.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think of your content, then, as any medium through which you communicate with the people who might use your products or services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your words define your brand. If you had know branding would you still recognise your brand via the words you use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you telling your story from your unique perspective, with a voice and style that&amp;rsquo;s clearly all you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you have to write your ideas out in complete sentences and complete paragraphs, it forces a deeper clarity of thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Words matter. Your words (what you say) and style (how you say it) are your most cherished (and, yet, undervalued) assets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brevity and clarity matter more than ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What matters now isn&amp;rsquo;t storytelling; what matters is telling a true story well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quality content means content that is packed with clear &lt;strong&gt;utility&lt;/strong&gt; and is brimming with &lt;strong&gt;inspiration&lt;/strong&gt;, and it has relentless &lt;strong&gt;empathy&lt;/strong&gt; for the audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Utility&lt;/strong&gt; — you clearly help your customers do something that matters to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inspiration&lt;/strong&gt; — your content is inspired by data. What credible source supports your main idea? Are there examples, data, real-world stories, relevant anecdotes, timely developments, or new stories you can cite?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Empathy&lt;/strong&gt; — you relentlessly focus on your customer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Utility × Inspiration × Empathy = Quality Content&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Words are your Web currency: they are a proxy, a stand-in for the important things you want to convey to your customers, and the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Habits are the invisible architecture of everyday life.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Start with empathy. Continue with utility. Improve with analysis. Optimise with love.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The first words&lt;/strong&gt; of every sentence should make a friendly first impression to encourage the reader to keep going.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Goal&lt;/strong&gt;. What&amp;rsquo;s your business goal? What are you trying to achieve? Anything you write should always be aligned with a larger (business or marketing) goal—even an individual blog post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reframe the idea to relate it to your readers.&lt;/strong&gt; Why does it matter to them? What&amp;rsquo;s in it for them? Why should they care? What&amp;rsquo;s the clear lesson or message you want them to take away? What value do you offer them? What questions might they have? What advice or help can you provide?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Organize.&lt;/strong&gt; What structure helps communicate your point? Some options are a list, a how-to guide, and a client narrative. Organize the outline or general architecture that suits that type of story best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Write to one person.&lt;/strong&gt; Imagine the one person you&amp;rsquo;re helping with this piece of writing. And then write directly to that person (using you, as opposed to using people or they).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Produce The Ugly First Draft.&lt;/strong&gt; Then walk away. Rewrite. Shape that mess into something that a reader wants to read. Give it a great headline or title. Have someone edit. One final look for readability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Publish, but not without answering one more reader question: what now?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The more you think about what you want to say, and plan for it, the easier it is to say.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If I&amp;rsquo;m really struggling, it&amp;rsquo;s usually not about the writing—it&amp;rsquo;s about the thinking.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“An hour with a fresh mind is worth five hours of fog.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before you begin the writing, be sure you know the purpose or mission or objective of every piece of content that you write. What are you trying to achieve? What information, exactly, are you trying to communicate? And why should your audience care?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some writers —including me— write as a way to figure out what we think. You, too, might develop your thoughts through writing, and you might not always have a clear sense of what exactly you want to say until you&amp;rsquo;re knee-deep in the water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Helps to first jot down thoughts to try to find a focus and points in support of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why am I creating this? What&amp;rsquo;s my objective? What is my key take on the subject or issue? What&amp;rsquo;s my point of view?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why does it matter to the people you are trying to reach?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In some cases that key point becomes the headline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might have more supporting points in a book or longer piece of content, but you should still be able to describe the key point in a single sentence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“great writing isn&amp;rsquo;t written, as much as assembled.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I almost always write an outline, even if it&amp;rsquo;s only a scribble on a piece of paper,” Doug Kessler said in an interview with me. “It helps me plan the arc of the story and the flow,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good writing serves the reader, not the writer. It isn&amp;rsquo;t self-indulgent. Good writing anticipates the questions that readers might have as they&amp;rsquo;re reading a piece, and it answers them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Good writing (and therefore crafting good experiences) requires us to understand and have empathy for our audience, their situation, their needs and goals.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What matters now is creating useful content that solves customer problems, shoulders their burdens, eases their pain, enriches their lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watch how customers behave. See what problems they have. “Look for patterns.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spend time with your customers or prospects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be a natural skeptic. A powerful question is, Why? Why do you do things that way? Why do you feel that way?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use a customer-centric POV.&lt;/strong&gt; Replace I or we with you to shift the focus to the customer&amp;rsquo;s point of view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Put your reader into the story. Put your reader—or someone just like your reader—into the story. You might share an anecdote about someone grappling with a problem your piece solves, or set up a scenario your reader will recognise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Describe a problem your reader can relate to. Set a stage. Ask a question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tell a specific, simple story really well, aligned with a bigger idea and broader strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good, pathologically empathic writing strives to explain, to make things a little bit clearer, to make sense of our world—even if it&amp;rsquo;s just a straightforward product description.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clarity of writing usually follows clarity of thought. So think what you want to say, then&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clarity of writing usually follows clarity of thought. So think what you want to say, then say it as simply as possible.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simplicity comes primarily from approaching any writing with empathy and a reader-centric point of view to begin with—&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Designing with your words, rather than fitting words into a design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;White space is a prerequisite, not a luxury. Large chunks of text are formidable and depressing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make your words the hero of your design, rather than adding them to a completed design the way a supermarket baker pipes a name into the blank field on a prebaked birthday cake from the case. Pasting words into a blank space without respecting their role in a design is called the lorem ipsum approach,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That approach treats the content as secondary to the design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a marketer, design and content aren&amp;rsquo;t separate processes; they are actually key parts of the same process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find a Writing Buddy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;good writing is more about thinking, rewriting, and keeping your focus relentlessly on the reader&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Know the Difference between Active and Passive Voice&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;passive means that something is being done to something,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;passive means that something is being done to something, instead of that something doing the action on its own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generally you want to use the active voice, or active writing, instead of the passive voice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ditch weakling verbs in favor of bold action words if you want to breathe life into your writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;an adverb describes more fully what&amp;rsquo;s going on with the words around it. An adverb often (but not always) ends in ly—&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Often you can ditch an adverb if you also ditch a weakling verb in favor of livelier one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use should have, not should of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep your verb tense consistent throughout; don&amp;rsquo;t switch around between present, future, past tenses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If everyone is thinking alike, then somebody isn&amp;rsquo;t thinking” (George S. Patton)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use who for people, which for things, and that for either people or things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;just don&amp;rsquo;t refer to a nonperson as who.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;your content is not about storytelling, it&amp;rsquo;s about telling a true story well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your story should be the steel-infused backbone of whatever content or social media presence you ultimately create&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Incidentally, focusing on your bigger story also helps you communicate strongly what makes you truly unique. (B-school types might call this, depending on the situation, your value proposition, positioning, or unique selling proposition.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;clearly communicating what makes you unique helps position you for long-term success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is unique about our business? What is interesting about how our business was founded? About the founder? What problem is our company trying to solve? What inspired our business? What aha! moments has our company had? How has our business evolved? How do we feel about our business, our customers, ourselves? What&amp;rsquo;s an unobvious way to tell our story? Can we look to analogy instead of example? (See Rule 19.) What do we consider normal and boring that other folks would think is cool?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And most important: relay your vision. How will our company change the world?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tell the Story Only You Can Tell&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem with all of these samples is that they could be describing a hundred different companies, rather than one unique company. What sets you apart? What&amp;rsquo;s unique about your story? Don&amp;rsquo;t tell me who you are—tell me why you matter to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Start telling the stories that only you can tell, because there&amp;rsquo;ll always be better writers than you and there&amp;rsquo;ll always be smarter writers than you. There will always be people who are much better at doing this or doing that—but you are the only you,” author Neil Gaiman&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Innovation is often the act of taking something that worked over there and using it over here.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generating brand awareness. The effort is largely centered on creating awareness of the company&amp;rsquo;s larger story, because you want people to know about and be familiar with your company—what it is and what it stands for. You&amp;rsquo;re not trying to generate sales directly from such articles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adobe&amp;rsquo;s CMO.com. Also, American Express&amp;rsquo;s OPEN Forum, which publishes information designed to help small business owners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As much as possible, your content should show, not tell. It should show your product as it exists in the world—&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be an advocate for your audience. What are you trying to get out of the interview for the benefit of your audience—the people who will consume this piece of content you&amp;rsquo;re creating as a result of an interview? If it&amp;rsquo;s something specific, make sure you open with a question that answers the biggest&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Converse, don&amp;rsquo;t interview. The best podcast hosts converse with their guests instead of interviewing them. They start out with a planned question or two and then let the response dictate the conversation. “Be prepared, but don&amp;rsquo;t read off a script,” suggests Kerry O&amp;rsquo;Shea Gorgone, who hosts the weekly MarketingProfs podcast, Marketing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Superlatives can make for great interview fodder. Questions like, “What&amp;rsquo;s the more interesting/best/baddest/most controversial/greatest/worst” can give you some great material to work with. Other favorite questions of mine: How did you get interested in this line of work/program/etc.…or How did you wind up here?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People&amp;rsquo;s journeys are always interesting—both to themselves and to others. And they can reveal some interesting bits of color about a person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shut up already. Your job is to draw the interviewee out, so try to speak less and let the other person speak more. Try not to interrupt unless it&amp;rsquo;s to ask a clarifying question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We take the trust our community places in us very seriously. Credibility is perhaps the most important trait of great curation. So don&amp;rsquo;t worry about spreading bad info. If it says “Upworthy,” you can share it with confidence, knowing that it checks out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Mark Twain&amp;rsquo;s 10-Sentence Course on Branding and Marketing.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tom Bentley, “Mark Twain&amp;rsquo;s 10-Sentence Course on Branding and Marketing,” MarketingProfs, July 15, 2013, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.marketingprofs.com/articles/2013/11152/mark-twains-10-sentence-course-on-branding-and-marketing&#34;&gt;www.marketingprofs.com/articles/2013/11152/mark-twains-10-sentence-course-on-branding-and-marketing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seek out primary, not secondary sources. A primary source is an original research project, or the originator of an idea or statement. A secondary source quotes the original source.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generally, the more recent the research, the more appealing it is. Try to avoid anything older than four years, since it&amp;rsquo;s likely to be stale. In some fast-evolving industries—mobile or social media, say—avoid anything more than two years old.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wikipedia is not a credible source&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are merely regurgitating content from elsewhere without adding your take, that&amp;rsquo;s not curation—that&amp;rsquo;s aggregation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A robot can aggregate content, but only a human can tell me why it matters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sections you create in your own words should be longer than any sections you&amp;rsquo;re quoting. Quote short passages or a short section of the original piece only—don&amp;rsquo;t reprint the whole enchilada. You&amp;rsquo;re curating parts, not reprinting the whole. The idea is to give your readers the gist of another piece so you can share your take on why it matters, or why it&amp;rsquo;s important, or what else to consider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I were linking to an article on marketer Mack Collier&amp;rsquo;s site, I&amp;rsquo;d link his name to his main URL at MackCollier.com, and I&amp;rsquo;d separately link to the curated article as well. Even if in the future he moves content around, he likely won&amp;rsquo;t change or lose his domain name. So a reader could still click on Mack&amp;rsquo;s name, arrive on his site, and search for the article there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ground Content in Data&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data puts your content in context and gives you credibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google&amp;rsquo;s Ngram Viewer is more obscure, but it lets you search and graph words and phrases from a vast number of books that Google has scanned in public libraries to populate its Google Books search engine (&lt;a href=&#34;https://books.google.com/ngrams)&#34;&gt;https://books.google.com/ngrams)&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s a useful (if quirky) tool for finding trends over a much longer time frame than measured in Internet time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;write every tweet as you would speak it…to your girlfriend, boyfriend, significant other, dog, cat, goldfish swimming in its fishbowl—or whoever you can imagine in the room with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Content hack: Try reading each sentence backward, instead of the usual way. Doing so jars your brain to consider each word independently, allowing you to spot typos more readily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Follow the company you want to work for on LinkedIn and you&amp;rsquo;ll not only discover what their business goals and priorities are, but also the words and phrases they use to describe these objectives,” Nicole suggested in an email interview.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Companies want to hire people who have an understanding of who they are and what they do,”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nicole says. “If you already sound like them they&amp;rsquo;ll be more apt to reach out to you if you&amp;rsquo;re already talking their talk.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider the key words you want to be known for, and optimize your profile by including those words in your headline and summary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.marketingprofs.com/opinions/2014/25214/dont-be-this-person-on-linkedin-headline-donts-and-dos&#34;&gt;www.marketingprofs.com/opinions/2014/25214/dont-be-this-person-on-linkedin-headline-donts-and-dos&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It uses you and your repeatedly, which makes it clear that the email isn&amp;rsquo;t about TaskRabbit, it&amp;rsquo;s about me—how TaskRabbit can help me. Subtle difference (maybe), but a critical one (definitely).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.practicalecommerce.com/articles/65858-E-mail-Marketing-in-2014-How-to-Avoid-Spam-Folders&#34;&gt;www.practicalecommerce.com/articles/65858-E-mail-Marketing-in-2014-How-to-Avoid-Spam-Folders&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing Landing Pages Less Is So Often More&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Match the message to the promise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet 45 percent of the landing pages that were evaluated failed to repeat the email&amp;rsquo;s promotional copy in the headline. If you sell someone on a promise, make sure that the first thing she experiences after taking action based on your promise doesn&amp;rsquo;t tell a whole ’nother story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep your headline benefit-driven.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A product-driven headline highlights what your product or service will do; a benefit-driven headline tells customers what your product or service will do for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Why the Title Matters More Than the Talk,” Upworthy Insider (blog), May, 19, 2014, blog.upworthy.com/post/26345634089/why-the-title-matters-more-than-the-talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speak to your audience. Who is your audience? Whom do you want to attract? And—just as important—whom do you not want to attract? All good content is rooted in a clear understanding of your audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the main headline on your page should communicate that customer-centric value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember: your value is not what you do or what you sell, it&amp;rsquo;s what you do for your customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use words your audience uses. You don&amp;rsquo;t need to embellish what you do. Use words that are familiar to your potential customer. Did you notice that Dropbox uses stuff instead of files, data, photos, and so on? I suppose it could&amp;rsquo;ve come up with a more sophisticated sounding word (maybe assets? property? resources? content?). But stuff really does cover all the things we all have stored on our computers, phones, and tablets. And that&amp;rsquo;s how many of us refer to all those things, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing the About Us Page When It&amp;rsquo;s Not Really About You The key to a successful About Us page sounds paradoxical: the best About Us pages aren&amp;rsquo;t really about the company; instead, they focus on relaying who they are in relation to the visitor. All good content puts the reader first, and that&amp;rsquo;s no different on your About Us page. In other words, About Us gives you a chance to talk about yourself, but always in the context of what you do for your customers. What burdens you help them shoulder, what problems you solve for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best infographics are entertaining, educational, and intrinsically useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Infographics should be based on fact, not merely opinion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best infographics have a hypothesis and narrative at their core. That sounds high-minded, doesn&amp;rsquo;t it? But it just means that you need to home in on the key idea you want your data to express. Write a kind of thesis statement. Then outline the main data points you want to use that support your thesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lay out the narrative with an eye toward information architecture. This means organizing your information in a way that flows logically, without undue complexity. Create an outline that highlights your key ideas in a narrative form. You might be tempted to skip this phase and go straight to design. But mapping is the critical step to creating an infographic that tells a meaningful story and doesn&amp;rsquo;t read as a jumble of numbers and drawings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“When you go to an art gallery, you notice little plaques next to the artwork that share crucial information to the artwork itself,” said Jarski. “Now imagine, you&amp;rsquo;re looking at Van Gogh&amp;rsquo;s Starry Night and the plaque beside offers details about the Mona Lisa. Jarring, right? The images and text need to make sense together.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing Better Blog Posts&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This is like asking if the quality of food in a restaurant matters. Writing is the primary determinant of the success of the post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep headlines tight. Guy suggests headlines of four or five words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time it well. Usually the best time for publication is between 8 and 10 a.m. weekdays, in the time zone where your readers live, Guy says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use bullets and numbered lists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use an interesting approach. Remember the mandate in Rule 8: good writing has logic and structure. But the structure itself can help to draw your readers in; revisit Rule 8 for some ideas about approaches and organizing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Show up. Half of blogging is consistency, or just showing up on a regular basis. As writer and content marketer Barry Feldman told me: “Write. Write now. Write a lot. Write freely. Write what you feel. Write first and edit second. If you want hits, you need to keep going up to the plate and swinging.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Buffer expanded its blogging strategy, focusing on lifehacking, business, customer service, and other topics alongside social media, because he realized it was key to getting access to a larger audience, he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2014, Buffer split its blogging efforts into two blogs, refocusing on social media tips in its main blog (blog.bufferapp.com) and launching a second blog it calls Open (open.bufferapp.com) as an expanded, more general outlet to talk about company culture and lifehacking tips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Reaching our audience&amp;rsquo;s audience is a big goal for us,” Leo said, a strategy he said was inspired by Rand Fishkin&amp;rsquo;s content marketing manifesto at Moz.com. “The reason for doing this is that ultimately it&amp;rsquo;s the best way how your brand and your audience can grow. You don&amp;rsquo;t limit yourself to just a certain audience, but you make sure that your content is relevant to your audience&amp;rsquo;s audience at all times.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.marketingprofs.com/charts/2014/25006/blog-best-practices-and-benchmarks&#34;&gt;www.marketingprofs.com/charts/2014/25006/blog-best-practices-and-benchmarks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing Annual Reports (or Annual Wrap-Ups)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The reader doesn&amp;rsquo;t turn the page because of a hunger to applaud.” Write something that encourages them to keep following you, and get a little more involved in your story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Start with some basics: Who did we grow to become in the past year? What changed? What didn&amp;rsquo;t? How have we evolved since our founding? What have been our biggest successes and our crushing failures? What&amp;rsquo;s commonplace to us that might be interesting to others?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HubSpot&amp;rsquo;s 2013 Year-in-Review. The Boston-based technology company produced a magazine-like look back at some of its key achievements of the previous year. What it is. Produced with a tool called Uberflip, HubSpot&amp;rsquo;s 2013 Year-in-Review reads more like an issue of People magazine than a business-to-business company production.1 Magazine sections include financial information, charitable efforts, events, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.warbyparker.com/annual-report-2013&#34;&gt;www.warbyparker.com/annual-report-2013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;mailchimp.com/2013/#by-the-numbers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;blog.bufferapp.com/from-0-to-1000000-users-the-journey-and-statistics-of-buffer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Content Tools&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;using off-line tools eliminates friction between the writer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Draft (draftin.com) was started by engineer Nathan Kontny to help people become better writers. I like the on-demand copyediting feature (which is kind of like an Uber for editing). I also like the Hemingway mode (based on the line “Write drunk, edit sober” often attributed to him), which doesn&amp;rsquo;t allow you to delete anything you&amp;rsquo;ve written.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scapple (literatureandlatte.com/scapple.php) is from the folks at Scrivener. It&amp;rsquo;s designed to help you brainstorm by mapping and tracking ideas and identifying connections between them. It&amp;rsquo;s not exactly a mind-mapping tool for writers, but it&amp;rsquo;s close.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Editing Tools&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grammarly (grammarly.com) bills itself as an automated proofreader and “your personal grammar coach.” It&amp;rsquo;s both a Web app and a plug-in for Word and Outlook, and so it is fairly robust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ProWritingAid (prowritingaid.com) is an online writing coach that flags spelling and grammar errors, clichés, and redundancies; it also checks for plagiarism and readability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Economist Style Guide (economist.com/styleguide) is one I fell in love with at its first line: “The first requirement of The Economist is that it should be readily understandable.” And that was only the start of our relationship. It goes on to offer great, practical, real-world advice for content of any type. Word nerds will appreciate its commentary and updates via Twitter, too (twitter.com/econstyleguide).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dragon Naturally Speaking (Nuance.com) is speech recognition software, which is a way to capture a first draft for those who either think better by talking or who can&amp;rsquo;t take the time to write something out. “It helps me write twice as fast and the writing is better because the tone is more conversational,” Paul Gillin told me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google Authorship&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although Google Authorship may not improve the rank of a page, it can increase traffic simply by making the search listing more prominent. And it&amp;rsquo;s not hard to set up. There are two links involved: (1) a link from the written page to the author&amp;rsquo;s Google+ profile page, and (2) a link from the author&amp;rsquo;s Google+ profile page to the blog or website. The first link must include a special tag, rel=“author.” The second link must appear in the Contributor To section of the author&amp;rsquo;s About page on G+. That&amp;rsquo;s it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TinEye (tineye.com) is a reverse image search engine. Upload an image and it can identify its source and how it&amp;rsquo;s being used and modified. It&amp;rsquo;s handy to identify an original photographer or source, but also handy if you&amp;rsquo;re looking for a higher-resolution version of an image you want to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Epilogue A writer who waits for ideal conditions under which to work will die without putting a word on paper. —E. B. White Done is better than perfect.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Smartcuts</title>
        <link>https://azharkhan.in/notes/smartcuts/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2016 21:34:41 +0100</pubDate>
        <author>azhar932@icloud.com (Azhar Khan)</author>
        <guid>https://azharkhan.in/notes/smartcuts/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Notes taken from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/20910174-smartcuts?from_search=true&#34;&gt;Smartcuts: How Hackers, Innovators, and Icons Accelerate Success&lt;/a&gt; by Shane Snow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whereas by dictionary definition shortcuts can be amoral, you can think of smartcuts as shortcuts with integrity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abagnale took shortcuts and regretted it. Franklin used smartcuts and got his face on a $100 bill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m convinced that true success has more to do with our becoming better people and building a better world while we do these things than it does with the size of our bank accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I see this book as a simultaneous hat tip and counterpoint to some of the great success and innovation literature out there (check out shanesnow.com/booklist for my recommendations). It’s a re-analysis and first codification of the ways rapid success has happened throughout history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;patterns of lateral thinking (smartcuts)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The players eliminated resistance by breaking the big challenge (acquire something valuable like a TV) into a series of easier, repeatable challenges (make a tiny trade).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Startups that pivot once or twice raise 2.5x more money, have 3.6x better user growth, and are 52% less likely to scale prematurely.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mentorship is the secret of many of the highest-profile achievers throughout history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sam Walton, founder of Walmart, studied and stole moves from master retailers fabulously well. He openly admitted it. “Most everything I’ve done, I’ve copied from someone else,” he said. The problem is that two people can study the same business model, watch the same video, or even take the same advice from a mentor, and one person might pick up critical details that the other misses. The late literary giant Saul Bellow would call someone with the ability to spot important details among noise a “first-class noticer.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oscar Wilde once said, “Experience is the name everyone gives to their mistakes.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If you’re not failing you are either very lucky, very good, or not pushing the boundaries enough,” Staats says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All great successes make mistakes along the way. NBA star Michael Jordan missed more than 9,000 shots and lost 300 games in his career. He was the best, and he failed a lot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crucially, experts tended to be able to turn off the part of their egos that took legitimate feedback personally when it came to their craft, and they were confident enough to parse helpful feedback from incorrect feedback. Meanwhile novices psyched themselves out. They needed encouragement and feared failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tough part about negative feedback is in separating ourselves from the perceived failure and turning our experiences into objective experiments. But when we do that, feedback becomes much more powerful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They know, because they got the feedback early, and often. “Speed is an essential part of our game,” Leonard explains. “The rapid feedback . . . it’s non-stop.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an age of platforms, creative problem solving is more valuable than computational skill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the saying, attributed to Dr. Seuss, goes: “It is better to know how to learn than to know.”*&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You can build on top of a lot of things that exist in this world,” David Heinemeier Hansson told me. “Somebody goes in and does that hard, ground level science based work. “And then on top of that,” he smiles, “you build the art.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best way to be in the water when the wave comes is to budget time for swimming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grant would know. He wrote the book on the subject. In his bestseller, Give and Take, he presents rigorous research showing that a disproportionate number of the most successful people in a given industry are extremely generous. From medical students to engineers to salespeople, his studies find givers at the top of the ladder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The number one problem with networking is people are out for themselves,” says Scott Gerber, founder of the Young Entrepreneur Council, who coined the term superconnector.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Superconnecting is about learning what people need, then talking about ‘how do we create something of value.’”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No matter the medium or method, giving is the timeless smartcut for harnessing superconnectors and creating serendipity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Design for Extreme Affordability,” or how to create products for people who live on less than a dollar a&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Innovation is about doing something differently, rather than creating something from nothing (invention) or doing the same thing better (improvement).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key feature of disruptively innovative products is cost savings (either time or money). But the key ingredient behind the scenes of every disruptive product is simplification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like Holmes, hackers strip the unnecessary from their lives. They zero in on what matters. Like great writers, innovators have the fortitude to cut the adverbs. This is why Apple founder Steve Jobs’s closet was filled with dozens of identical black turtlenecks and Levi’s 501 jeans—to simplify his choices. US presidents do the same thing. “You’ll see I wear only gray or blue suits,” President Barack Obama told Michael Lewis for his October 2012 Vanity Fair cover story. “I don’t want to make decisions about what I’m eating or wearing. Because I have too many other decisions to make.” I don’t want to make decisions about what I’m eating or wearing? How could that possibly make one better at governing? Or problem solving? And isn’t variety the very spice of life? What about creativity? Or not going crazy? What he’s talking about has been proven in experiments led by Dr. Kathleen Vohs of the University of Minnesota, experiments that show that making lots of tiny choices depletes one’s subsequent self-control. Students who were forced to decide between products for long periods of time had significantly less willpower afterward than classmates who answered random questions instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notes: 1) understanding minimalism&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apparently, patience and willpower, even creativity, are exhaustible resources. That’s why so many busy and powerful people practice mind-clearing meditation and stick to rigid daily routines: to minimize distractions and maximize good decision making.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, Apple’s iPod won the MP3 player war with breakthrough simplicity, both in physical design and how the company explained it. While other companies touted “4 Gigabytes and a 0.5 Gigahertz processor!” Apple simply said, “1,000 songs in your pocket.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creativity comes easier within constraints&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;as Musk likes to say, “The first step is to establish that something is possible; then probability will occur.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Generally speaking, if you’re gonna make something ten percent better than the way things currently are, you better be great in sales and marketing, because you’re gonna have to talk people into changing their behavior for a very marginal increase in value,” explains Astro Teller.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If, on the other hand, you make something ten times better for a large number of people—you really produce huge amounts of new value—the money’s gonna come find you. Because it would be hard not to make money if you’re really adding that much value.” This is exactly&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Big causes attract big believers, big investors, big capital, big-name advisers, and big talent. They force us to rethink convention and hack the ladder of success. To engage with masters and to leverage waves and platforms and superconnectors. To swing and to simplify, to quickly turn failure into feedback. To become not just bigger, but truly better. And they remind us, once again, that together we can achieve the implausible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a first-class noticer, a master of tiny details about how shoes are put together and how consumers on the street think about them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was in the water before the wave came.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>The Challenger’s Almanac</title>
        <link>https://azharkhan.in/notes/challengers/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2016 21:34:41 +0100</pubDate>
        <author>azhar932@icloud.com (Azhar Khan)</author>
        <guid>https://azharkhan.in/notes/challengers/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Thought’s and notes from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/28605442-the-challenger-s-almanac?ac=1&amp;amp;from_search=true&#34;&gt;The Challenger’s Almanac&lt;/a&gt; by Mark Anderson.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;thoughts&#34;&gt;Thoughts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hate to admit it — I had this book on my shelf for a few years before I finally came to read it. Wish i&amp;rsquo;d picked it up sooner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re anything like me then the stories in this book will make a lot of sense to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you believe in quality over quantity. If you consider yourself a creative thinker — an artist, a maker or an entrepreneur of sorts — with a tendency to challenge the way things are done, then you&amp;rsquo;ll have a lot of time for this book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the companies featured were started by people questioning the way things are done. Using lateral thinking as their weapon, they&amp;rsquo;ve made it their mission in life to solve problems personally faced. Problems they are passionate about trying to fix — and not just for the money — but because they genuinely want to do good in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book is also packed full of related reading and recommended talks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Challenger brands are &lt;strong&gt;businesses with purpose&lt;/strong&gt;. Businesses who are  prepared to break the rules. Businesses that manage to blend having a positive impact on the world with being financially successful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Often naivety leads companies to new and creative ways of working.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most challenger companies begin life as &lt;strong&gt;side projects&lt;/strong&gt;, created through passion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They lack experience and a natural right to create. &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;re not experts but why should that matter&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All successful people fail.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Transparent sense of purpose and a force of good challenging ethics and ideology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Solving problems. Seeing something that needs to be done better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Proof of concept&lt;/strong&gt; — &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;I started telling people my idea as if it already existed. I had customers. I had a business&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;. Reminds me of &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Buffer&amp;rsquo;s landing page POC&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ask for help&lt;/strong&gt; — you can&amp;rsquo;t do it alone. Passion and excitement is a great bargaining tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You need a purpose — that you love and others can believe in — and an idea to make something better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Procrastiwork&lt;/strong&gt; — work you do when you are putting off other work. &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;The work you do when you&amp;rsquo;re procrastinating is probably the work you should be doing for the rest of your life&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let tiny victories pave your path. By doing so your path will present itself. Don&amp;rsquo;t set overly ambitious goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Procrastiwork&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; can help you maintain momentum with client work as you switch from project to project to keep excitement high.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take time to understand what you love about the work your doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;The Holstee Mainifesto&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; – a company should be built around a lifestyle rather than the other way around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seeing business as a way to make an impact on the world and contribute to a cause you feel strongly about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only person you should listen to is the customer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ask for advise from other companies and people that inspire you. You&amp;rsquo;ll be surprised at how much people are willing to share about what they have learnt and the mistakes they&amp;rsquo;ve made.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Figure out your message and put your energy into getting it across.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;The most satisfying thing is knowing your business is a force of good and can make a difference to a cause you feel strongly about.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Find a mentor&lt;/strong&gt; — someone who has been there before and can stear you in the right direction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On public speaking&lt;/strong&gt; — understand your audience so you can get an idea of what they want to know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10,000 hours&lt;/strong&gt; — in order to be an expert you have to spend 10,000 hours (approx. 10 years) practicing it. An idea taken from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/3228917-outliers&#34;&gt;Outliers by Malcom Gladwell&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Trust your own judgement. Have faith in your decisions. Take advise from people you respect an be prepared to act on it.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Behind most Challenger brands there is usually someone on a mission to solve a problem they have encountered in their lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Challengers change the way we think, act, feel, see and behave using design to express their vision.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not about building it fast, but building it right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s not the government who is going to solve our environmental issues, it&amp;rsquo;s business.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Everytime I&amp;rsquo;ve done the right thing for the environment, i&amp;rsquo;ve made a profit&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; — Yvon Chouinard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Business is the most powerful man-made force on the planet, so it is important for businesses to use that power to do the most good. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if a business is the biggest. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if it&amp;rsquo;s the fastest growing. It matters if a business is the best in the world at being the best for the world.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;What matters most is not simply the ability to make money, but the ability of a business to create value for its customers, employees, community, the environment and other stakeholders.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Share your mission with your employees. This creates more engaged employees and spurs innovative thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Expand your network. Share your results. Put your practices and policies into writing, this helps everyone adhere to goals as the company grows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Anyone Paradigm&lt;/strong&gt; — &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;We are full service, and or company will serve anyone&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;.  Don&amp;rsquo;t try and serve everyone, this approach isn&amp;rsquo;t strategic enough. Focus on serving quality customers, not a quantity of customers. It&amp;rsquo;s better to know who you will not serve, and what services you will not perform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A company can become strategic by narrowly defining who it is they serve best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recognising you have limitations is strategic, not weak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Business strategy is to know your greatest skill, and offer the world only that.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The &amp;ldquo;what we believe&amp;rdquo; in document&lt;/strong&gt; — helps to keep the wrong customers out. If they do not align with your beliefs, they might not be the best fit for your company. A good way to find the right clients. Alignment is key.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of enterprise is to produce value for customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you care more about customers than profit, then you can take a limited number of clients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be honest.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Make products that last&lt;/strong&gt; — simple sustainable design. Design that matters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People remember good stories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn the rules in order to break them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pursue passion projects.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most valuable currency is &lt;strong&gt;time not money&lt;/strong&gt;. Don&amp;rsquo;t strive for the biggest profits but instead find the time for things that matter to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pursue and develop creative ideas.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Creativity is our currency; something we promise and our clients expect&amp;rdquo;. Get away from you desk if you want this to work.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;We all need time and space to experiment and cultivate creativity if our ideas are really going to be fresh&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Allowing time and space for incidental thoughts, ideas, conversations that you only get from actually meeting someone really does reap rewards and nurture lasting, valuable relationships.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Profit with principles. It&amp;rsquo;s not just economic profit, but a positive social and environmental impact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have a vision. Consider the type of Culture you want to create.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t command but collaborate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nurture and develop individuals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make money not your only priority.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be honest and transparent with your communication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without purpose you have no meaning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great achievement is talent plus preparation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Practice isn&amp;rsquo;t the thing you do once you&amp;rsquo;re good. It&amp;rsquo;s the thing you do that makes you good&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; - Malcolm Gladwell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t be afraid to prototype in public&lt;/strong&gt;- &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;put yourself out there and see where the velcro sticks&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;A brand is not a logo, or a pantone colour. A brand ius a promise.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;How much can I give, rather than How much can I take.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Know what it is you&amp;rsquo;re trying to say, say clearly, and then do what you said you were going to do, when you said you were going to do it. That is the rule for business.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;They [Entrepreneurs] are not just risk takers, they are believers in the unproven, untested, and the unlikely&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;A misconception of business is that you need bags of experience to start.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Naïve Optimism&lt;/strong&gt;: To not get sidetracked by what can&amp;rsquo;t be done. There are no rules. Only opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;All too often, leaders of companies are willing to Sacrifice people to save the numbers, rather than sacrificing the numbers to save the people.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Leadership is the choice to offer protection to those in our care. It&amp;rsquo;s simply, &amp;lsquo;I will risk my life for the good of my people&amp;rsquo;. That&amp;rsquo;s why you own the title of leader.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;The genius of one never sold anything. As human beings, we&amp;rsquo;re better together.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Why you do what you do, not what you do. That&amp;rsquo;s a good place to start.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*&amp;ldquo;We all have to question, and be willing to break the rules.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;If you want to remain number 1 you have to think like number 2.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Fear regret, not failure.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;rdquo;..find your &amp;lsquo;why&amp;rsquo;, identify your mission, define your belief, write your manifesto. Do all these things, and then build upon them.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>