<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blognotes on Azhar Khan</title>
    <link>https://azharkhan.in/tags/blognotes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blognotes on Azhar Khan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>azhar932@icloud.com (Azhar Khan)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>azhar932@icloud.com (Azhar Khan)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2020 17:59:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://azharkhan.in/tags/blognotes/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
      <item>
        <title>5 question problem solving strategy</title>
        <link>https://azharkhan.in/notes/5-question-problem-solving-strategy/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2020 17:59:33 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>azhar932@icloud.com (Azhar Khan)</author>
        <guid>https://azharkhan.in/notes/5-question-problem-solving-strategy/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Having a clearly defined, repeatable strategy is the easiest way to make problem solving more tolerable”, says Nicholas C. Zakas in &lt;a href=&#34;https://humanwhocodes.com/blog/2020/02/how-i-think-about-solving-problems/&#34;&gt;How I think about solving problems&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s Nicholas’s five questions to ask yourself:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is this really a problem?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does the problem need to be solved?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does the problem need to be solved now?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does the problem need to be solved by me?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is there a simpler problem I can solve instead?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nicholas uses these 5 questions to help make decisions and prioritise his actions. They help make him more efficient at problem solving and in general, happier with the outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He says that; “Each one of these questions helps reveal something about the problem, so you can make progress or even avoid the problem altogether.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like this pragmatic approach to problemn solving. It reminds me that it’s not just about tackling a problem head on, but about considering the problem from many different perspectives. In some cases, that means figuring out whether it’s a problem worth solving in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To quote &lt;a href=&#34;https://fs.blog/2013/10/inversion/&#34;&gt;Charlie Munger&lt;/a&gt;; “..many hard problems are best solved when they are addressed backward.” It reminds me of &lt;a href=&#34;https://azharkhan.in/articles/2019-review/#the-power-of-inversion&#34;&gt;the power of inversion&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;source&#34;&gt;Source&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://humanwhocodes.com/blog/2020/02/how-i-think-about-solving-problems/&#34;&gt;How I think about solving problems&lt;/a&gt; by Nicholas C. Zakas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Building With Your Users</title>
        <link>https://azharkhan.in/notes/building-with-your-users/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 11:18:40 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>azhar932@icloud.com (Azhar Khan)</author>
        <guid>https://azharkhan.in/notes/building-with-your-users/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;”Build with your users, get quick feedback loops, and iterate after. We are so biased and imperfect as humans that it&amp;rsquo;s impossible to get it right from the start. Also, you might get it right, but you might miss other bigger opportunities. Focus, start quickly, and put your product in front of users and let the free market destroy it or love it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This was taken from an interview with &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/vinrob&#34;&gt;Robin Vander Heyden&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.indiehackers.com/&#34;&gt;Indie hackers&lt;/a&gt; where he discusses the success of his company &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.manypixels.co/&#34;&gt;ManyPixels&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;resources&#34;&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.indiehackers.com/interview/finding-inspiration-abroad-shipping-fast-and-growing-to-50k-mo-e55f6feafd&#34;&gt;Finding Inspiration Abroad, Shipping Fast, and Growing to $50k/mo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>1,000 true fans</title>
        <link>https://azharkhan.in/notes/1000-fans/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2016 21:34:41 +0100</pubDate>
        <author>azhar932@icloud.com (Azhar Khan)</author>
        <guid>https://azharkhan.in/notes/1000-fans/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If you have roughly a thousand true fans (or  super fans), you can make a living — if you are content to make a living but not a fortune.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;em&gt;true fan&lt;/em&gt; is defined as a fan that will buy anything you produce.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You have to create enough each year that you can earn, on average, $100 profit from each true fan.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You must have a direct relationship with your fans — i.e they must pay you directly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you keep the full $100 of each true fan, then you need only 1,000 of them to earn $100,000 per year. That’s a living for most folks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A thousand customers is a whole lot more feasible to aim for than a million fans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The number 1,000 is not absolute — I.e if you only earn $50 per year per true fan then you would need 2,000 fans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This idea has been made possible by peer-to-peer communication and payment systems — in other words the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;blockquote class=&#34;PullQuote PullQuote--right&#34;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
            “Everyone has access to excellent tools that allow anyone to sell directly to anyone else in the world.”
            
            
        &lt;/p&gt;
        
            &lt;figcaption&gt;&amp;mdash; Kevin Kelly&lt;/figcaption&gt;
        
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This new technology permits creators to maintain relationships, so that the customer can become a fan, and so that the creator keeps the total amount of payment, which reduces the number of fans needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever your interests as a creator are, your 1,000 true fans are one click from you. As far as I can tell there is nothing — no product, no idea, no desire — without a fan base on the internet. Every thing made, or thought of, can interest at least one person in a million — it’s a low bar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;takeaway&#34;&gt;Takeaway&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1,000 true fans is an alternative path to success other than stardom.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instead of trying to reach the narrow and unlikely peaks of platinum bestseller hits, blockbusters, and celebrity status, you can aim for direct connection with a thousand true fans.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On your way, no matter how many fans you actually succeed in gaining, you’ll be surrounded not by faddish infatuation, but by genuine and true appreciation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It’s a much saner destiny to hope for. And you are much more likely to actually arrive there.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>