<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Year in Review on Azhar Khan</title>
    <link>https://azharkhan.in/tags/year-in-review/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Year in Review on Azhar Khan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>azhar932@icloud.com (Azhar Khan)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>azhar932@icloud.com (Azhar Khan)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 14:17:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://azharkhan.in/tags/year-in-review/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
      <item>
        <title>2019 in Review</title>
        <link>https://azharkhan.in/articles/2019-review/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 14:17:30 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>azhar932@icloud.com (Azhar Khan)</author>
        <guid>https://azharkhan.in/articles/2019-review/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;With 2019 almost over, it’s time to reflect on what have been another busy 12 months. This is a chance to take note of my successes and failures and pinpoint potential areas for improvement. I’ll do so by asking three simple questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What went well this year?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What didn’t go so well this year?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What did I learn this year?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’ve ever read Atomic Habits by James Clear, then these questions will sound familiar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By reflecting on these questions I hope to better understand where I need to focus my time and energy in the year ahead. Life moves fast and I find time and time again that slowing down is the best way to stay ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-went-well-this-year&#34;&gt;What went well this year?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, let’s start with the good stuff that has happened this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;work&#34;&gt;Work&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year I’ve been lucky enough to work with a select few clients who allow me to work on the things I’m most interesting in and learn new technologies whilst doing so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I built two new websites I’m particularly pleased with – &lt;a href=&#34;https://hub.seedtribe.com/&#34;&gt;SeedTribe Hub&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jobs.angelinvestmentnetwork.co.uk/&#34;&gt;AIN Jobs&lt;/a&gt; – both using a new tech stack (React, Gatsby, GraphQL and Sanity). I’ve learned much more about programming in JavaScript in the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really wasn’t expecting to pick up basic React concepts and GraphQL so quickly. Testament to the Gatsby and Sanity docs and the many Slack channels I’ve joined this year. Everyone in the Sanity Slack Group and in particular &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/kmelve&#34;&gt;Knut&lt;/a&gt; from the Sanity core team have been incredibly helpful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;newsletter&#34;&gt;Newsletter&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had a good year with &lt;a href=&#34;https://harrycresswell.com/newsletter/&#34;&gt;my weekly newsletter&lt;/a&gt; which I published consistently, only missing four weeks due to holiday. I’ve started to notice the impact of this commitment. Although the number of you subscribing is still modest that number has increased substantially. I haven’t done much at all in the way of marketing, so I’m pleased so many of you are enjoying it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ashleyo_brien/status/1180073230809419776?s=20&#34;&gt;Ash was kind enough to Tweet about it&lt;/a&gt; and several of you have emailed with positive feedback and questions. I’ve no doubt it’s been a great way to connect with other designers and developers and start conversations about common interests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;in-detail&#34;&gt;In Detail&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year one of my intentions was to move In Detail forward and together with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/beaniemajor/&#34;&gt;Beanie&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://lukeharvey.co.uk/&#34;&gt;Luke&lt;/a&gt; we’ve successfully done that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We made a big decision to pivot the business model by narrowing our focus to helping our clients collaborate with designers to design bespoke engagement rings. It’s was a bit of a no brainer, as this is what most of our clients are coming to us for help with. It just took some courage to drop the jewellery box content which we’d become well known for and change direction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our transition was heavily inspired by a simple idea – ‘do one thing and do it well’ – which we borrowed from a concept called &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ted.com/talks/rory_sutherland_perspective_is_everything&#34;&gt;goal dilution&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the business modal simplified, we have clarity in our focus and a clear direction for our content. The business now feels more aligned with our current values concerning consumerism and the environment – buy less and make what you do buy last a lifetime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;health&#34;&gt;Health&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This years been a good year for health. Since last year I’ve doubled my number of runs and I’m now tracking all my sessions. Alternating run days with yoga days has reduced the strain on my body and keep my knees happy. By tracking sessions I can now spot where I’m doing well and where I need to focus more time and effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also started climbing again which feels good. It’s fun to solve problems unrelated to design and code for a change. For me climbing creates mind space, it’s calming and methodical, which I like. I’m sure it must improve capacity to work in some way too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On that note I continued to meditate most mornings. I’ve no doubt meditation helps with focus and improves my ability to think clearly, particularly in more stressful situations or when I’ve had a lot on my plate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;travel-and-family&#34;&gt;Travel and family&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In February I spent a few days in France skiing with my dad and sister. It’s not often we spend time together so it was a real treat. We also took a family trip to Corfu in the summer which was a lot of fun. It’s the first time we’ve all been away together since I was small.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rebekka and I took the van to England for a road trip and headed up to Northumberland and The Lake District. I have to admit, after initially feeling slightly underwhelmed by the idea of a holiday in my own country I couldn&amp;rsquo;t have enjoyed it more. England is a magical place, full of history, incredible people and beautiful landscapes. I’m proud to call it my home country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;finance&#34;&gt;Finance&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I finally paid off my student loan. I should have done it years ago but kept putting it off. It feels good to be debt free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of this I also took the time to set up a self invested personal pension (SIPP). I’ve realised how important it is to think about your future when you work for yourself. After all, nobody else will do it for you. With the power of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Compound_interest&#34;&gt;compound interest&lt;/a&gt; it makes sense to do this stuff sooner rather than later. The more time you have the more your money can make.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;dark-sky-collab&#34;&gt;Dark Sky Collab&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matt and I collaborated again on &lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/dark-sky/sets/cold-harbour-ep&#34;&gt;the latest Dark Sky release&lt;/a&gt;. Really pleased with how this one turned out. It’s been 8 years since we first joined forces for Black Rainbows EP and we’ve worked on pretty much every release since.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matt’s music is the source of so much inspiration and I’m proud to work on this project together with him. It’s given me a platform to think more conceptually, work with complete creative freedom and do something totally different from building websites, for a change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-didnt-go-so-well-this-year&#34;&gt;What didn’t go so well this year?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now for the things that didn’t quite go to plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;writing&#34;&gt;Writing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wrote a fair amount this year but didn’t publish much of it, particularly in the way of articles. I felt the pressure to replicate and improve the writing I had some success with in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also began thinking more about the impact of my writing. I questioned the quality of what I had written and wondered if I was just adding to the noise with transient words of little value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overthinking can hold you back but at the same time I feel it’s important to be responsible for what we put out into the world and make a conscious contribution for the right reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I felt more comfortable writing short technical notes that do away with design opinions. It’s felt more like keeping a wiki and they’re much easier to write. I’d like to write more about design in 2020 but most likely from more of a technical/coding perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;courses&#34;&gt;Courses&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I dipped in and out of a few courses but didn’t get fully into anything, so I want to make this a priority for 2020. This year felt busier than most and because of that I found less time for structured learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To start the year on the right foot I picked up &lt;a href=&#34;https://beginnerjavascript.com/&#34;&gt;Beginner JavaScript by Wes Bos&lt;/a&gt; which I hope to use it to fill the gaps in some of my knowledge, particularly on ES6 and practice building more with vanilla JavaScript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also bought &lt;a href=&#34;https://scrimba.com/g/greact&#34;&gt;Advanced React Bootcamp&lt;/a&gt; on Scrimba for the same reason. Although I’ve been working with React quite a bit this year, some of the more advanced concepts still leave me scratching my head. This is something else I need to work on in 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;german&#34;&gt;German&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought having a German girlfriend might help me pick up the language relatively quickly, but it turns out it’s far more difficult than I had anticipated. Potentially more so than JavaScript, for me anyway! I found the basics pretty easy but the conjugations and incessant changing of words caused by the article completely throw me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although I’ve stuck with my daily 30 minutes of Duolingo this year, I need to work on my understanding of the grammar and find an environment where I can speak more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn’t make that happen this year so I’m planning on finding an online tutor, perhaps from &lt;a href=&#34;https://preply.com/&#34;&gt;Preply&lt;/a&gt; to help me out. It seems more realistic than going back to to the classroom to study as it takes up less time in the day. Either way I’m committed, my progress is just much slower than expected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;type-design&#34;&gt;Type design&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not been a great year for my side project Type Services. I haven’t worked on the project at all this year and I’ve been trying to pin-point why that is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I realise that perhaps I’ve moved on from the style of type I was creating and feel the world of variable fonts and type designed for screens is more where I’m at. It’s certainly more in line with the rest of my work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that it feels like a good time to re-align my aim for the project and evolve it into something new. I think about typography and type design a lot so I’ve no plans to stop designing type, I just think a new direction might help reignite my passion for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;networking&#34;&gt;Networking&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve never been a great one for networking. I’m quite happy spending time on my own which can be both good and bad. This year was the first time I’ve felt like my lack of networking might be holding me back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d like to get out there a bit more next year by joining a Meetup or making at least one industry event. I plan to make more of an effort in 2020 and hope to meet more creative folk in the real world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;social-media&#34;&gt;Social media&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m a big fan of Twitter but I still can’t seem to make a habit of posting regularly. It always comes as an afterthought and I rarely feel I have anything interesting to add to the conversation. Like a lot of things I’m sure this is down to my own lack of self confidence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generally I find it helps to plan content ahead, but with social media that somehow feels a bit contrived and not spontaneous enough. Perhaps some form of scheduling could help. Or some sort of content plan where I stick to &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/harrycresswell/status/1200881854703972352?s=20&#34;&gt;sharing helpful tips&lt;/a&gt; and leave it at that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve found my feet more in Slack channels this year. I feel more comfortable asking questions and helping others in that format. Perhaps that’s because it feels slightly more private and less like the whole world is watching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-did-i-learn-in-2019&#34;&gt;What did I learn in 2019?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technical skills aside, next I’ll outline some of the helpful ways of thinking I adopted this year which I feel have made a big impact to my progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;simplify-to-avoid-setbacks&#34;&gt;Simplify to avoid setbacks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of my biggest setbacks came from complexity. I spent far too much time fixing things like broken dependencies, trying to write monster articles then loosing interest, or using too many different tools that I didn’t actually need. That really held me back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I learned that by making things as easy as possible it’s far more likely you’ll achieve your goals. Often this comes from simplifying your process, taking on less obligations or focusing on fewer things. It’s well worth taking the time to think about what you can &lt;a href=&#34;https://sivers.org/subtract&#34;&gt;Subtract&lt;/a&gt; in order to improve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this in mind I made a number of big changes to my design and productivity workflow. I switched to Figma for UI prototyping, which allowed me to ditch 3 tools in Sketch, Invision and Abstract. I also jumped on the Notion bandwagon which replaces Evernote, Airtable, Trello and Pocket. Notion, is literally an all-in-one tool, it’s fantastic. Because of these changes I’m now far more focused and productive and I save money too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also went back to basics with my build process, replacing Gulp in many of my project starters with NPM scripts. In the case of Hugo I switched to using the built in assets pipeline. I’m trying to think more consciously about dependencies and whether they are absolutely necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has reduced the number of issue I’m having. It’s saved me time as it’s made my build times quicker. And it’s allowed me to focus more on doing stuff and less on fixing things. Taking the time to think about ways I can improve my processes instead of jumping in with little thought has been invaluable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;consistency-is-still-the-key&#34;&gt;Consistency is still the key&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consistency is an amazing thing. Whilst its importance is arguably be over played in UI design, it’s incredibly powerful for making improvements to your daily life and work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the improvements I made this year – particularly in my health, my newsletter and through learning new skills – were down to one thing, I was more consistent. I kept track of my habits and workouts in Notion and kept an eye on areas I was falling down so I could make improvements. A little bit each day definitely seems to go a long way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-power-of-inversion&#34;&gt;The power of inversion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://fs.blog/2013/10/inversion/&#34;&gt;Inversion&lt;/a&gt; is a powerful mental model which I’ve begun using more consciously. The idea is you turn a problem on its head, start with the desired outcome and work backwards to find the solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a great way to remove obstacles which may be standing in the way, and avoid obvious stupid mistakes. Often it starts with the simple question – ”what is my goal?” Then, consider the question - “what is preventing me from achieving this goal?”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thinking about what you want to avoid can be more effective for making progress than simply asking asking yourself – “what can I do to solve this problem?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;you-are-what-you-eat&#34;&gt;You are what you eat&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s been a long time since my body has felt as good as it has this year. I’ve spent a lot of time on my health and my diet and I’ve finally started to master what I need to put into my body and how to look after it properly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, much of this is based on the gut. IBS has plagued me for years, but since discovering the power of fermented foods, by reading &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/23013953-gut?from_search=true&amp;amp;qid=mVZRHNHpBT&amp;amp;rank=5&#34;&gt;Gut&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/24886264-cultured-food-for-health?ac=1&amp;amp;from_search=true&amp;amp;qid=FT9nTVtfqm&amp;amp;rank=2&#34;&gt;Cultured Food for Health&lt;/a&gt;, I’ve started to get a hold of these issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 3 K’s (as I like to call them) – Kimchi, Kombucha and Kefir – have been a real game changer. And whilst this might not work for everyone they’ve certainly helped me. I only wish I’d discovered this stuff sooner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2020 I’d like to spend more time learning about fermentation and giving it a go myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2019-in-numbers&#34;&gt;2019 in numbers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now for the numbers. I wish I’d recorded more but it’s not always easy to keep track of everything. Here’s what I have managed to keep track off this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;health-stats&#34;&gt;Health stats&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;104 recorded runs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;217 recorded yoga sessions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;33 hours and 92 minutes meditated&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;9,580 press-ups&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;131.5 recorded minutes in a headstand&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;work-stats&#34;&gt;Work stats&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;48 newsletters sent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4 articles published&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;12 notes published&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;learning-stats&#34;&gt;Learning stats&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;18 books read&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;56 hours of German on Duolingo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;environment-stats&#34;&gt;Environment stats&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;23.87 trees planted via Ecosia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;18 trees planted via donation to TreesforCities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;travel-stats&#34;&gt;Travel stats&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;6 countries visited – England, Germany, Netherlands, Belgium, France and Greece (Corfu)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;recommendations-for-2019&#34;&gt;Recommendations for 2019&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Best Documentary&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aCv29JKmHNY&#34;&gt;Inside Bill’s Brain: Decoding Bill Gates&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Best Documentary runner-up&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iX8GxLP1FHo&#34;&gt;The Great Hack&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Favourite article&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;https://ethanmarcotte.com/wrote/the-world-wide-work/&#34;&gt;The World-Wide Work&lt;/a&gt; by Ethan Marcotte&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Favourite book&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/48419903-brief-answers-to-the-big-questions&#34;&gt;Brief answers to the big questions&lt;/a&gt; by Stephen Hawking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Favourite book runner-up&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/21083719-human-universe&#34;&gt;Human Universe&lt;/a&gt; by Brian Cox&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Favourite Series&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XrC4vDcWmxk&#34;&gt;One Strange Rock&lt;/a&gt; by Darren Aronofsky&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Favourite Series runner-up&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=s9APLXM9Ei8&#34;&gt;Chernobyl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Favourite quote&lt;/strong&gt;: “The only thing I know is that I know nothing” - Socrates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Music most listened to&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/dark-sky/sets/cold-harbour-ep&#34;&gt;Cold Harbour EP&lt;/a&gt; by Dark Sky&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Favourite exhibition&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.barbican.org.uk/whats-on/2019/event/ai-more-than-human&#34;&gt;AI: More than Human&lt;/a&gt; at the Barbican&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;final-words&#34;&gt;Final words&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was my second time &lt;a href=&#34;https://harrycresswell.com/articles/year-in-review/&#34;&gt;writing a year in review&lt;/a&gt; and once again it’s been a valuable exercise. It’s helped me to put my foot on the brakes and take stock of my accomplishments or lack thereof. In some way or another it’s helped me better understand myself, in terms of what I care most about, what no longer serves me, where I can improve and where I should focus my efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I referred to my &lt;a href=&#34;https://harrycresswell.com/articles/2018-review/&#34;&gt;2018 in review&lt;/a&gt; throughout this year, using it to keep tabs on my progress. In 2020 I hope to do the same with this one, using it to move more consciously through life, make better decisions and practice gratitude wherever possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To that end I’d like to say thanks to everyone who has helped make this year a great success, I’m grateful to you all. Wishing you all a very happy new year and here’s to the next decade. Thanks for reading!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>2018 in Review</title>
        <link>https://azharkhan.in/articles/2018-review/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 14:10:29 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>azhar932@icloud.com (Azhar Khan)</author>
        <guid>https://azharkhan.in/articles/2018-review/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p class=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;
    With 2018 drawing to a close, I’ve decided to share my first Year in Review.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a chance to reflect and review my successes and failures over the past year, in a conscious effort to evaluate my progress, make improvements and insure I stay focused on the right stuff in the year ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having struggled with the pressures of a goal setting approach in previous years, I was drawn to this method after reading &lt;a href=&#34;https://jamesclear.com/atomic-habits&#34;&gt;James Clear’s Atomic Habits&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The format of my Year in Review is almost the same as James’. Nothing new, but new for me. I hope it will help refine my processes and set myself up for a productive year ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My Year in Review will answer the following three questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What went well this year?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What didn’t go so well this year?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What did I learn?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My review will also include my intentions for 2019 and the areas I wish to focus on, which I plan to use as a guide in the year to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-what-went-well-this-year&#34;&gt;1. What went well this year?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Writing.&lt;/strong&gt; I managed to write 13 articles across &lt;a href=&#34;https://azharkhan.in/&#34;&gt;harrycresswell.com&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@harrycresswell&#34;&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;, and record notes on most of what I’ve learnt from courses (some of which I’ve published). My weekly Newsletter has been one of my most consistent projects this year, with the audience growing steadily and the content starting to show a clear direction. If I can continue on this path in 2019 I’ll be very happy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In Detail.&lt;/strong&gt; Perhaps the most successful project I work on, undoubtably down to the incredible mix of people involved. We all bring a different skill set and continue to use it as a vehicle to learn, experiment and collaborate. 2019 is set to be another good year for &lt;a href=&#34;https://indtl.com/&#34;&gt;In Detail&lt;/a&gt; with more energy focused on creating useful content for our readers, providing a service and doing what we can to make the jewellery industry more sustainable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JavaScript.&lt;/strong&gt; I finally got my act together and began to learn programming. Having made several attempts in the past I found taking some time out to focus on one thing, along with &lt;a href=&#34;https://watchandcode.com/p/practical-javascript&#34;&gt;Gordon Zhu’s Practical JavaScript course&lt;/a&gt; to be the key.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m starting to see how the value gained in understanding a logical language like JavaScript can transcend and make improvements in other areas of my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yoga and running.&lt;/strong&gt; Although I didn’t track my yoga sessions this year, they were consistent. I think the fear of back pain drives my practice, as I’m all too aware how bad health makes everything else impossible. I’ve found a pattern of practicing yoga and running on alternate days to work best for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Travel.&lt;/strong&gt; In 2018 I spent time in 7 different countries: England, Germany, United States, Portugal, Luxembourg, France and Austria. Luxembourg being the only new addition to the list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notable places I enjoyed spending time this year were Lisbon for its food, people and good weather, Strasbourg for its architecture and amazing clash of cultures and New York for its relentless energy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I continued to spend much of my time in Hamburg which I now consider my home for part of the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;year-in-numbers&#34;&gt;Year in Numbers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Published Articles: 13&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Published Notes: 10&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sent Newsletters: 40&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Runs: 52 (147.2 Miles)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Books Read: 12&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-what-didnt-go-so-well-this-year&#34;&gt;2. What didn’t go so well this year?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Loss of family.&lt;/strong&gt; In January I lost my Grandpa to Dementia. Although his final years were difficult, he had a long and happy life. I always admired his positive outlook on the world and fantastic ability to ignore what’s not important. I must remember him for how he was when I was growing up and try and forget those final years. I will miss him greatly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meditation and Climbing.&lt;/strong&gt; I’ve put these two together as they share one thing in common – I failed miserably at both. In 2017 these two disciplines where a real lifeline for me. Climbing helped me with problem solving and taught me how to be more methodical with my approach to every day challenges. For building physical strength it’s one of the best practices I’ve found.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meditation, meanwhile, helped me with my composure, stress and focus. For one reason or another both fell by the wayside in 2018. I’d like to get back into a regular habit and disapline of practicing both next year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Type Services.&lt;/strong&gt; After a successful end to 2017 – where I released my first 3 typefaces in as many months – in 2018 I failed to release a single font. I must remind myself that good things take time, and whilst I have been slowing working away on a couple of new typefaces, I haven’t dedicated nearly enough time to the project. In 2019 I’m planning to change that and hope to deliver products more consistently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Car Accident.&lt;/strong&gt; Following 3 solid weeks of work converting our van to a camper, a car slammed into the back of us on the autobahn. It was our first day in a 2.5 month journey around Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mentally this was a huge challenge, having rented out our apartments and facing life without a home whilst we waited for our van to be fixed. But looking back we’re fortunate we survived the crash. And the experience certainly helped us to face challenges head on and grow in ourselves. I’m glad to report the van is now back on the road.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learning German.&lt;/strong&gt; I had a positive start to the year, beginning A1.2 German at Deutsch Akademie in Hamburg. Sadly I failed to keep this up throughout the year, although my German girlfriend assures me my conversational German is improving – albeit slowly. 2019 Los geht’s!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;3-what-did-i-learn&#34;&gt;3. What did I learn?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I learned a lot in 2018. Here are some of the most important takeaways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The best way to learn something new is to do a bit each day.&lt;/strong&gt; Before now I had ‘Learn JavaScript‘ somewhere on my todo list. It wasn’t until I stuck with Gordon Zhu’s Practical JavaScript course that I realised how ridiculous this must sound.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JavaScript is hard. Like any language it’s something you need to work at, on a daily  basis if possible. To make this happen I took 2 solid months off work towards the end of this year and worked on my JavaScript every day, following Gordon‘s course almost exclusively. I’ve by no means got the language in its entirety, but it’s starting to click.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this reason my biggest achievement this year may have been ‘learning how to learn‘ – by sticking with it and showing up regularly. I realise this approach applies to any practice in life or anything you wish to improve at.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my case with JavaScript, rather than saying “Learn JavaScript” it might be be more useful to say “Practice your JavaScript each day” or “Spend 10 minutes a day building something with JavaScript”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It’s important to step away from what you know and do something completely different.&lt;/strong&gt; In September I took 3 weeks off work and converted a 2013 VW Transporter panel van into a camper, together with my girlfriend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s been over 10 years since I last worked with wood and the first time I’ve ever modified a vehicle or worked with electrics. There’s something incredibly cleansing about working with your hands. It was a welcome break from my usual day-to-day in front of a computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process taught me the importance of stepping away from a screen and applying myself to new problems, in different ways to those I’m used to. It also taught me the importance of action. No matter how much research you put in before hand, there’s something to be said for just getting started. Every situation will present its own set of problems which often are impossible to predict.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to deal with setbacks and a change of plans.&lt;/strong&gt; Life doesn’t always run smoothly. It often happens the way you least expect it. And you’ll sometimes find yourself living outside of your own control and well beyond the scope of your plans. This year this manifested itself in the form of the car crash I mentioned earlier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what important lessons did I take from this? Setbacks are unavoidable. Plans will inevitably change, it’s how you react that’s most important. Even if you try to, it’s wasted energy trying to control everything. A better way is to focus on how you respond to the situation you find yourself in. If you can find the positives in a challenging situation, then you will thrive in life. No matter what the challenge, there are lessons to take away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Success is the result of compound investment.&lt;/strong&gt; Over the years I’ve started countless projects and failed to stick at them. The problem was, I struggled to realise that success takes time and regular input.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently my good friend told me he was thinking about chucking in his music career to do something else, I said to him “It’s too late to stop now.” What I meant was; I could see how far he’s come with his sound and how much work he’s put in. It’s only a matter of time before all that time and effort pays off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year I learnt the importance of seeing things through from start to finish and that success is the result of compound investment, not necessarily just some great idea or a moment of luck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;top-recommendations-in-2018&#34;&gt;Top Recommendations in 2018&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Best Book:&lt;/strong&gt; Atomic Habits by James Clear&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Best (free) Course:&lt;/strong&gt; Practical JavaScript by Gordon Zhu&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Best article:&lt;/strong&gt; Using Sketch Libraries to build a better UI design system&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Best Documentary:&lt;/strong&gt; Free Solo by Elizabeth Chai Vasarhelyi and Jimmy Chin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;intentions-for-2019&#34;&gt;Intentions for 2019&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rather than goal setting for any fixed outcome – which I’ve had little success with in past years – I’m using an intentional approach which focuses more on how I carry myself through each day, how I practice and how I conduct myself during my commitments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m treating these as a set of principles which I can use to guide my process and apply to various aspects of my life and work. The idea is to make lots of small improvements that I hope will have a big impact in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My guiding principles for 2019 are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be consistent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Slow down&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Focus on less&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Document what you learn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give back what you can&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be Consistant.&lt;/strong&gt; Consistency is everything. For me being consistent means showing up regularly (ideally daily) to practice the things I do. This is the best way I know how to form good habits and improve any chance of success I might have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doing a little bit each day to compound long term returns not only applies to financial investment but investments in your health, education, work, relationships and progress in life. This is an important concept I try to take with me into yoga  and meditation practice, running, learning JavaScript, German or whatever it may be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Slow Down.&lt;/strong&gt; I find I’m the most productive in life when I slow down and take time to reflect on whatever it is I’ve been doing. I find myself picking up concepts faster when I take the time to fully understand what’s in front of me. I retain more when I take on less.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2019 I want to continue this philosophy. Using various methods such as note taking, habit tracking and writing from memory, to recall the things I’m learning, be more methodical and slow down the fast pace of life. This is the best way I found to prevent myself from speeding through life on auto-pilot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Focus on less.&lt;/strong&gt; In 2019 I’m challenging myself to open fewer browser tabs, spend less time on social media, commit to fewer obligations and add less items to my todo list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, I want to focus my energy on a select few projects that I see as having the most potential and designate specific time blocks in my day to lower value tasks, like reading articles online, opening emails, use social media, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My aim is to find a deeper approach to work and get more done each day by focusing on fewer things. Like most people I’m increasingly aware of how my online consumption is effecting my ability to concentrate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Document what you learn.&lt;/strong&gt; My intention is to do a better job of documenting processes, recording workouts and improving habit tracking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having little success with the various apps out there to help you do this, I’ve adopted a manual process of entering my daily workouts in an Airtable base, using the calendar view to record my workout sessions. I also make it a priority to document things I’m learning which I feel are important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope this will help me form daily habits and meeting my goal of becoming more consistent in the things I do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Giving back what you can.&lt;/strong&gt; In a world full of mindless consumption and little care for the environment, I feel it’s more important than ever to create and share great work that educates, to give back and strive for positive change in the world. Positive contribution has become the centre of everything I want to achieve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A question I’ll be asking myself regularly this year is; ”Am I having a positive impact on the people around me and the world we live in?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2019 my aim is to be more mindful about my consumption, continue with donations to &lt;a href=&#34;https://onetreeplanted.org/&#34;&gt;onetreeplanted.org&lt;/a&gt; and seek out new ways to support positive change in any way I can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;areas-of-focus-for-2019&#34;&gt;Areas of Focus for 2019&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With my intentions set, I want to briefly outline the key areas I wish to apply my focus, whilst keeping these intentions in mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In previous years I’d make a list of specific things I want to achieve each quarter, though often by the 4th quarter I’d find myself with much of my list remaining. So this year I want to avoid that kind of pressure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Specific areas I wish to focus on:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Health:&lt;/strong&gt; Resume a regular climbing and meditation practice. Continue running and practicing yoga on alternate days of the week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Writing:&lt;/strong&gt; Publish at least 15 well researched articles. Stick with my weekly newsletters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learning:&lt;/strong&gt; My primary focus is on JavaScript programming and pursuing my interest in JAMStack technology.  From a personal stand point I’d also like to continue improving my conversational German.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Design/Development:&lt;/strong&gt; Move In Detail forward. Build more in ReactJS and with Gatsby. Get more creative with my type design.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Travel:&lt;/strong&gt; I had a good year for travel in 2018 so I’d like to continue this and try and make it to at least 4 different countries. Travel is the best way I know to keep a broad and open mindset.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;final-words&#34;&gt;Final words&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading my first Year in Review. I hope you’ve found this helpful in some capacity. It’s been a great chance to be more mindful and reflect on this past year whilst creating a plan for an intentional year ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re not yet writing your own Year in Review, perhaps after reading this one you might consider writing one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or comments you can reach me on &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/harrycresswell&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;, I’d be happy to hear from you. Likewise, please consider sharing this with anyone you feel might find it useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the best for 2019. Here’s to a productive and prosperous new year.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>A Year in Review</title>
        <link>https://azharkhan.in/articles/year-in-review/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 30 Dec 2018 12:25:59 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>azhar932@icloud.com (Azhar Khan)</author>
        <guid>https://azharkhan.in/articles/year-in-review/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Whilst writing my &lt;a href=&#34;https://harrycresswell.com/tags/year-in-review/&#34;&gt;year in review&lt;/a&gt; this year it seemed like a good idea and perhaps a useful exercise to outline exactly what this means to me – why I write one and the approach I use to write it. I hope this may in some way be helpful for you too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is very much my own take to what has become an annual practice for many and I follow a format that has, so far, worked well for me. Here’s everything I can tell you about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-i-write-a-review-of-my-year&#34;&gt;Why I write a review of my year&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was drawn to the idea of writing an annual review after reading Atomic Habits by James Clear, in which he proposes that habits are the compound interest of self-improvement, and that success is the product of good daily habits. In other words, the effects of your habits multiple as you repeat them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;James writes the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Improvement is not just about learning new habits, it’s also about fine-tuning them. Reflection and review ensures that you spend your time on the right things and make course corrections whenever necessary.“&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might boil this down to the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build good daily habits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reflect to identify what’s working and what isn’t&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fine-tune, re-focus, drop ineffective habits where necessary&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve and become the person you wish to be&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With reflection we get a better sense of perspective, we become more self-aware and identify areas in need of improvement. It helps you reframe your identity and become better at whatever it is you choose to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-i-write-a-review-of-my-year&#34;&gt;How I write a review of my year&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use the same format as James for my own review, it’s simple and works well, so I see no reason to change it. By review my progress, I aim to answer the following three questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What went well this year?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What didn’t go so well this year?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What did I learn this year?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;James has his own reasons for asking these three questions, which I encourage you to explore further, however I’d like to outline what these questions mean to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By asking “what went well this year” I ensure the year ends on a positive note.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s so easy to focus on the bad stuff and forget the good things that have happened throughout the year. This question realigns those negative thoughts, encourages a positive mindset and confirms a successful year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By asking “What didn’t go so well this year?“ I hope to identify the areas I need to improve, so I can begin the year ahead with clear purpose and intention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Shane Parish writes in &lt;a href=&#34;https://fs.blog/tgmm/&#34;&gt;The Great Mental Models&lt;/a&gt;;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You can’t improve if you don’t know what you‘re doing wrong. Admitting to your failures is the hardest part. But by doing so we can learn from them and avoid making them again.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, by asking “What did I learn this year?” I remind myself that I’m making progress and heading in the right direction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s easy to fall into the trap of thinking you haven’t achieved much or that you haven’t made progress. The answers to this question help prevent these insecurities from manifesting and help give you a much needed boost for the year ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;final-words&#34;&gt;Final words&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever you choose to call it, taking the time to reflect on your achievements by writing a year in review is a helpful exercise. It’s an exercise that will help you learn more about yourself and identify areas in need of improvement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reflection can bring a sense of perspective and writing a review each year can help you identify whether you are becoming the person you wish to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more on this check out my &lt;a href=&#34;https://harrycresswell.com/tags/year-in-review/&#34;&gt;year in review archive&lt;/a&gt; and pick up a copy of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/40121378-atomic-habits&#34;&gt;Atomic Habits&lt;/a&gt; if you haven’t read it already. It’s an important book full of actionable advice.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>